<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: existentialism | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/existentialism/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-04T00:48:49-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Afterlife?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/30/an-afterlife/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-30T19:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/30/an-afterlife</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am not a religious man, yet I find myself curious about the prospect of an afterlife. Is
there something beyond this life, in this dimension, in this universe? While I don't believe
in the traditional conception of an afterlife (one's soul ascends to a blissful place, where
it inhabits all space and time for eternity), I do like to think we live on beyond the
time we take our last breath.</p>

<p>In ninth grade, I graduated to a Sunday School class which resembled a forum &mdash;
discussion-based learning. A retired history teacher, a Public Defender, and a social
worker led the discussions in this class. The dialogue probed our most deeply held beliefs
and asked profound questions about  life, spirituality, goodness, happiness, beauty, and
other similar topics.</p>

<p>One day, we were discussing the afterlife. The normal answers dominated the conversation:
"When one dies, one's soul ascends into Heaven to be with one's family members and with
God," and "We exist everywhere and with everyone. We watch over those we love and help
them live good lives." When the question came to me, I wasn't sure how to respond. Can an
atheist believe in an afterlife? If so, did I?</p>

<p>I hadn't given it much thought before, but I pondered it for a moment and concluded, "An
individual's afterlife is the culmination of the memories others have of the individual.
It is the legacy that individual leaves behind and the impact that individual had on those
he or she encountered."</p>

<p>The more I thought about it, the more it made sense. If we don't have souls, how do we
explain this legacy of the afterlife concretely? The afterlife is not something experienced
by the deceased individual, but by everyone else he or she impacted.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='&#8220;They say you die twice, once when your
heart stops beating, and again when your name is said for the last time.&#8221;'>
I have not yet met anyone else who holds this belief I hold, but I invite you to explore
it and see of you can reconcile it with your beliefs about the afterlife. Banksy once
famously said (paraphrased by a friend): "They say you die twice, once when your
heart stops beating, and again when your name is said for the last time." I can't
believe there is something I will experience beyond my death, but I can believe that
others will experience their memories of me beyond my departure from this world.
</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
