<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-30T17:45:29+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dealing with Distraction]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/30/dealing-with-distraction/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T15:56:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/30/dealing-with-distraction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dealing with distraction for those of us who live with AD(H)D is a constant struggle, and
can be especially difficult for those of us who must daily solve large, complex problems.
This post describes what it is like to be a programmer with ADD and some strategies I&#8217;ve
developed to help make myself more effective.</p>

<p>To solve complex problems by programmatic means, one needs to be able to focus. To find
the best solution to any problem, one needs to be able to focus. In short, an effective
worker is one who can focus.</p>

<p>For those of us who live with the difficulties of AD(H)D every day, this fact - this
dependence upon a kind of mental discipline - is glaringly obvious. Our constant struggle
to focus means we are not as efficient as our non-ADD peers when asked to complete a
single task. We get distracted by the sound of the wind, the tap of a colleague&#8217;s fingers
on his desk, or the sound of people talking walking past our window. The slightest noise
or change (by a separate entity) in the visual landscape will cause us to loose our train
of thought nearly immediately.</p>

<p>For those of you who can focus relatively easily in distracting environments, I offer this
metaphor to help you understand a bit more of how it is it live with such an affliction.
Imagine you are swimming in a lake with a basketball. The depth at which you swim is your
level of concentration - the deeper you swim, the more focused you are and thus the less
susceptible to distraction you are. Imagine further that a day&#8217;s worth of work is like
swimming the length of the lake, and your goal is to swim as deeply as possible for as
far as possible. The problem is that you have to do all this while holding onto the
fully-inflated basketball. The longer you swim underwater, the harder it is to keep the
ball (and yourself) deep underwater. During your swim from one end of the lake to the
other, you are pulled up to the surface very frequently, only able to keep the ball
underground for a short while at a time. This is what it&#8217;s like to live and work with ADD.</p>

<p>The inability to focus on a given problem for more than a few minutes at a time causes
severe problems for all employees with ADD, but especially for developers who have to
delve into a problem, process it, and produce a solution quickly and efficiently.</p>

<p>The effectiveness of various solutions will vary person to person, but these helped me:</p>

<ul>
<li>Find a quiet, solitary place to work (avoid working in a place where people socialize)</li>
<li>Turn off all notifications when working (fetch updates at will instead)</li>
<li>Play calm, simple music without words, or work in a place where the background noise
doesn&#8217;t change</li>
<li>Keep the room cool in temperature</li>
<li>Work on one thing at a time and work until it is completed</li>
<li>Plan out finer details for a large project</li>
<li>Get enough sleep</li>
<li>Medicate with some sort of stimulant</li>
<li>Keep your workspace empty of clutter and visual distraction</li>
<li>Keep snacks by your desk (like almonds or dried fruits) to keep your energy up
throughout the day</li>
<li>Exercise to exhaustion at least every other day</li>
<li>Consciously avoid doing several things at once, like listening to a YouTube Lecture and
checking your Twitter feed on your phone at the same time</li>
<li>Avoid depressants like alcohol</li>
<li>Write or engage in a creative, exciting activity which asks for your full concentration</li>
</ul>


<p>Following all of these with ADD can even be a challenge, but limiting the frequency of
distracting stimuli goes a long way to achieving focus and increasing your productivity.</p>

<p>If you have other suggestions, hit me up on <a href="http://alpha.app.net/parkr">ADN</a> or
<a href="http://twitter.com/parkr">Twitter</a>. How do you cope with distractions?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Rid of Senate Prayer]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/09/get-rid-of-senate-prayer/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T18:17:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/09/get-rid-of-senate-prayer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier today, I was watching a <a href="http://www.c-spanvideo.org/program/SenateSession4967">C-SPAN video</a> of a U.S. Senate session on
February 1, 2012. This was the first time I had ever watched a Senate session
from the beginning and, to my surprise, they began with a prayer.</p>

<p>Hold up. A prayer? In a session of one of our government&#8217;s highest legislative
bodies?! I suppose I shouldn&#8217;t be too surprised, what with the (often crazy)
Religious Right getting after the government with Bible-backed policies and
all. It was nevertheless astonishing to see the institutionalization of religion
in our government.</p>

<p>I generally like our government, but this changes everything. Man, I was angry.
I felt betrayed and undermined - like I was worth nothing to anyone in D.C.</p>

<p>So I wrote to my senators:</p>

<blockquote><p>Dear Senator,</p>

<p>I wish to ask for the Senator&#8217;s thoughts on the opening prayer which begins a
Senate session. I have done my research and see that this prayer has been a
part of Senate procedure since 1789 and was recommended by Benjamin Franklin
about two years previous, but I question its place in our secular government.
It is, frankly, inappropriate that any governmental body in our United States
of America be so closely tied to one religious creed in a nation with many
hundreds and thousands of religious belief systems. I will not deny that
religion is a part of politics - a belief in a certain religious creed often
results in an election win - but it has absolutely no place in governance.
It is insulting to think that any one religion is given special treatment in
our governments.</p>

<p>I ask the Senator to introduce a bill which will put an end to this Senate
Prayer, for, while Mr. Franklin may have been right in 1789, he is most
certainly wrong now. We have moved past a blind reliance on God, and it is,
now more than ever, a hindrance on our Great Government.
God&#8217;s interference in our government has forced limited civil rights for
minorities, was a rationale for slavery, and is still fighting against a
Woman&#8217;s Right to Choose, a Citizen&#8217;s Right To Marry Whomever He or She Wishes,
Scientific Advancement in many fields and so on.</p>

<p>It is our imperative as citizens to think of each other first and to respect
the different viewpoints and beliefs of our fellow Americans. Honoring any
religion on our Senate floor is a betrayal of this principle, and it must be
stopped.</p>

<p>Thank you,<br />
Parker Moore<br />
Constituent</p></blockquote>

<p>If you care about religious freedom at all, I would urge you to do the same.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jekyll 1.0 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T00:59:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I&#8217;m proud to announce the release of Jekyll 1.0. There are a million
goodies and fixes to enjoy, and we&#8217;re (the still-active Jekyll core team
members: Tom, Matt and I) really excited to share this first major release
with you. Be sure to follow <a href="http://twitter.com/jekyllrb">@jekyllrb</a> for
updates on future releases and links to cool plugins.</p>

<p>Some quick highlights:</p>

<ul>
<li>New subcommands: new, build, serve, and import</li>
<li>Amazing new docs at http://jekyllrb.com (thanks to @cobyism)</li>
<li><code>jekyll new</code> creates a new scaffold so you can get blogging even faster</li>
<li>Drafts, i.e. posts without dates</li>
<li>New &#8220;excerpt&#8221; feature on posts</li>
<li>Timezone configuration</li>
<li>&#8216;gist&#8217; liquid tag</li>
<li>Source directory protection</li>
</ul>


<p>&#8230; and <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/v1.0.0/History.txt">so much more</a>!</p>

<p>We also have an <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/upgrading/">Upgrading</a> page that clarifies
some breaking changes and tips for upgrading to Jekyll 1.0.</p>

<p>As many of you know, Jekyll lay mostly stagnant for quite some time. At 0.11.2 and
0.12.0, it was pretty stable. It had some annoying bugs, but nothing much that
couldn&#8217;t be worked around or monkey-patched.</p>

<p>After using Jekyll last summer to help build
<a href="http://cals.cornell.edu">Cornell&#8217;s College of Agriculture and Life Sciences website</a>,
I took a renewed interest in seeing this project move forward. Last December,
Tom answered my offers to help with the development of Jekyll by adding me as
a contributor. I&#8217;m happy to say that it has come a long way since then, and
I&#8217;m very proud to be a part of a team that has pushed this project to new heights.</p>

<p>Thank you to everyone who submitted a pull request, and/or gave me advice along
the way. It has been great fun so far, and I look forward to working with you
all to push out future versions!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Afterlife?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/30/an-afterlife/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-30T19:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/30/an-afterlife</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am not a religious man, yet I find myself curious about the prospect of an afterlife. Is
there something beyond this life, in this dimension, in this universe? While I don&#8217;t believe
in the traditional conception of an afterlife (one&#8217;s soul ascends to a blissful place, where
it inhabits all space and time for eternity), I do like to think we live on beyond the
time we take our last breath.</p>

<p>In ninth grade, I graduated to a Sunday School class which resembled a forum &mdash;
discussion-based learning. A retired history teacher, a Public Defender, and a social
worker led the discussions in this class. The dialogue probed our most deeply held beliefs
and asked profound questions about  life, spirituality, goodness, happiness, beauty, and
other similar topics.</p>

<p>One day, we were discussing the afterlife. The normal answers dominated the conversation:
&#8220;When one dies, one&#8217;s soul ascends into Heaven to be with one&#8217;s family members and with
God,&#8221; and &#8220;We exist everywhere and with everyone. We watch over those we love and help
them live good lives.&#8221; When the question came to me, I wasn&#8217;t sure how to respond. Can an
atheist believe in an afterlife? If so, did I?</p>

<p>I hadn&#8217;t given it much thought before, but I pondered it for a moment and concluded, &#8220;An
individual&#8217;s afterlife is the culmination of the memories others have of the individual.
It is the legacy that individual leaves behind and the impact that individual had on those
he or she encountered.&#8221;</p>

<p>The more I thought about it, the more it made sense. If we don&#8217;t have souls, how do we
explain this legacy of the afterlife concretely? The afterlife is not something experienced
by the deceased individual, but by everyone else he or she impacted.</p>

<p><span class='pullquote-right' data-pullquote='&#8220;They say you die twice, once when your
heart stops beating, and again when your name is said for the last time.&#8221;'>
I have not yet met anyone else who holds this belief I hold, but I invite you to explore
it and see of you can reconcile it with your beliefs about the afterlife. Banksy once
famously said (paraphrased by a friend): &#8220;They say you die twice, once when your
heart stops beating, and again when your name is said for the last time.&#8221; I can&#8217;t
believe there is something I will experience beyond my death, but I can believe that
others will experience their memories of me beyond my departure from this world.
</span></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Mustn't Idle]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/22/we-mustnt-idle/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T04:12:12+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/22/we-mustnt-idle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our legacies on this Beautiful Earth are inextricably tied to the work we do, the
principles we stand for and the messages we spread. The apathetic nature of many of my
peers nowadays is heresy to the nth degree, and we can no longer stand idly by and watch
young people refusing to talk about the hard issues. If we’re to make any progress and
maintain this More Perfect Union, we had better get our act together and stand and fight
for the things we believe in.</p>

<p>It comes with a price, however. We must be informed. We must read the arguments of the
other side, debate them and reformulate our stance given the new evidence. In the same
way Newton used this inductive methods to formulate his three famous Natural Laws, we
must start with a problem we observe in our society, generalize a solution in the form
of legislation, judicial action or grassroots campaigning, and revise our message as new
information becomes available.</p>

<p>It is not enough to let Gov majors, English majors and law students run the country,
making sweeping decisions about how we may live our lives. It is not enough to defer to
those with means and wealth – those with the ability to run a traditional campaign for
public office and influence those in public office – in fact, it is the worst offense to
this Great Nation to allow the aristocracy of special interets to continue determining
the rule of law. We must stand up, as citizens, and fight for what sparks fire in our
bellies! We must stand up, as citizens, and say “enough is enough” to special interests
and lobbyists who control Washington. Now is our time. If our country is to change for
the better, it will be because we – the citizens – made our voices heard and fought with
much gnashing of teeth for what we believe in and what we know is right.</p>

<p>This is the imperative of our generation. Let us act!</p>

<p>This post was originally published on <a href="https://medium.com/i-m-h-o/d5bf40927b1a">Medium</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do Not Single Out the Democrats - This is About Everyone]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/01/do-not-single-out-the-democrats-equals-this-is-about-everyone/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-01T00:23:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/01/do-not-single-out-the-democrats-equals-this-is-about-everyone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just read an <a href="http://www.upworthy.com/omg-google-tucker-carlson-and-gay-marriage?c=fea">appalling story by <em>Upworthy</em></a> that singles out 10 Democratic
senators who do not support full marriage equality for gays and lesbians. This
article is an absolute disgrace. <em>Upworthy</em> (and the <em>Huffington Post</em> for that
matter) should not be singling out Democrats who do not believe in same-sex
marriage as though it&#8217;s some unnatural digression from the widely-accepted
democratic platform. No, they should be listing <strong>every</strong> senator that does
not support same-sex marriage.</p>

<p>It is not a fundamental tenant of the democratic platform. It is a fundamental
tenant of reason, of American law, and of human equality. There is no good
reason every congressperson should not support same-sex marriage. This is not
about party lines. This is about human dignity and equality in the eyes of the
law.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downtime is Good]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/02/11/downtime-is-good/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-11T22:43:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/02/11/downtime-is-good</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just started working as an intern at 6Wunderkinder a couple weeks ago.
I am by no means an expert in devops (hell, I have only dabbled with a little
sysadmin in the past - nothing too serious) and I don&#8217;t really know what goes
into keeping a huge series of server up and running. I can say, however, that
I know the customer&#8217;s side of things. I know what it&#8217;s like to be a user of a
service which periodically goes through downtimes of noticable lengths. (I know
I&#8217;m not the only one here so you will probably relate to this observation as
well.</p>

<p>So today there was a blip of downtime for Wunderlist, a really awesome task-
management application by 6Wunderkinder. During this downtime, it occurred to
me: downtime can help the visibility of an application or service.</p>

<p>Hear me out: when the service is running smoothly, few will actually talk about
it. When it goes down, Twitter blows up with complaints and &#8220;ZOMG MY LIFE IS
OVER&#8221; tweets. These tweets, in a way, promote the service. The more frustrated
the tweet, the more apparent it is that the tweeter cares about this service.</p>

<p>As one who sees these frustrated tweets often about many services, I can only
conclude that a little downtime here and there is a great way for outsiders
to gauge how awesome a service is: if it goes down and people are upset, then
the service is probably worth trying out (once it goes back up again). If the
service goes down and no one cares, then it probably isn&#8217;t worth your time.</p>

<p>So next time you see angry tweets, write down the name of that service and
check it out once everything is back in order. In all likelihood, you will
like the service, too, and you&#8217;ll be angrily tweeting next time it goes down.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s all about perspective.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Install rbenv on Ubuntu 12.04]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/02/06/install-rbenv-on-ubuntu-12-dot-04/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-06T21:31:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/02/06/install-rbenv-on-ubuntu-12-dot-04</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, I&#8217;ll admit it: I absolutely adore rbenv.</p>

<p>In light of this, I&#8217;ve been using it at my work at 6Wunderkinder the past couple weeks.
6W uses AWS like nobody&#8217;s business, and the Ubuntu EC2 instances I&#8217;ve been interacting
with are really bare-bones. So I wanted to write this script for you, the Ubuntu &amp; Ruby
user, in order for you to very quickly get up and running with rbenv &amp; the latest Ruby
MRI. Just copy it and run it.</p>

<figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Installing rbenv on Ubuntu 12.04</span></figcaption><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
<span class='line-number'>4</span>
<span class='line-number'>5</span>
<span class='line-number'>6</span>
<span class='line-number'>7</span>
<span class='line-number'>8</span>
<span class='line-number'>9</span>
<span class='line-number'>10</span>
<span class='line-number'>11</span>
<span class='line-number'>12</span>
<span class='line-number'>13</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class='bash'><span class='line'>sudo apt-get install zlib1g-dev openssl libopenssl-ruby1.9.1 libssl-dev libruby1.9.1 libreadline-dev git-core make make-doc
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">cd</span> ~
</span><span class='line'>git clone git://github.com/sstephenson/rbenv.git .rbenv
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">echo</span> <span class="s1">&#39;export PATH=&quot;$HOME/.rbenv/bin:$PATH&quot;&#39;</span> &gt;&gt; ~/.bashrc
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">echo</span> <span class="s1">&#39;eval &quot;$(rbenv init -)&quot;&#39;</span> &gt;&gt; ~/.bashrc
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">exec</span> <span class="nv">$SHELL</span> <span class="c"># Restart the shell</span>
</span><span class='line'>mkdir -p ~/.rbenv/plugins
</span><span class='line'><span class="nb">cd</span> ~/.rbenv/plugins
</span><span class='line'>git clone git://github.com/sstephenson/ruby-build.git
</span><span class='line'>git clone git://github.com/sstephenson/rbenv-gem-rehash.git
</span><span class='line'>rbenv install 1.9.3-p362
</span><span class='line'>rbenv rehash
</span><span class='line'>rbenv global 1.9.3-p362
</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>



]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Connect to 3G on simyo in Germany]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/01/30/connect-to-3g-on-simyo-in-germany/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-30T18:10:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/01/30/connect-to-3g-on-simyo-in-germany</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently signed up for simyo, a German cell provider. After installing the Nano SIM into my phone,
I noticed that the 3G connection to the mobile data network was failing. Got a weird error that said
I was not subscribed to a mobile data network. Which was obviously false.</p>

<p>So, I tweeted about it. Expecting a several-day delay in my support query from simyo, I totally resigned
to wait on mobile data until they got back to me. But luckily this new 6W family &amp; friends totally came
to my rescue. <a href="http://rafifyalda.id.au/">Rafif Yalda</a>, a former Wunderkind, totally came to my rescue in
<a href="https://twitter.com/rafifyalda/status/296664474885165056">a tweet</a>.</p>

<p>So if you ever run into a problem with your mobile network, ensure that your APN settings are correct.
In this case:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>APN: internet.eplus.de
</span><span class='line'>username: simyo
</span><span class='line'>password: simyo</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>THANK YOU RAFIF. This surely saved me many hours of frustration.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Favourite Apps in 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/01/03/my-favourite-apps-in-2012/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-03T01:36:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/01/03/my-favourite-apps-in-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below is a list of the apps I wouldn&#8217;t have wanted to live without this year.
To be fair to everyone, I&#8217;ve listed them in alphabetical order.</p>

<p>I know some apps are missing links to various versions, but if I didn&#8217;t use it,
then I felt it was best not to include a link to it on this list.</p>

<h3>101 Airborne (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/101-airborne/id531317549?mt=8">iPhone</a>)</h3>

<p>At this moment, this is one of only two games which I have installed on my iPhone.
I have thoroughly enjoyed playing this game, and it is incredibly well-done,
to boot.</p>

<h3>Diet Coda (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/diet-coda/id500906297?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>When I had to have the logic board in my MacBook Pro replaced, I had to hand in
my computer for a week. I am practically addicted to development, and this app
by Panic, Inc. of Portland, Oregon, served me well during those tough times.</p>

<h3>Dropbox (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dropbox/id327630330?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/install">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Dropbox gives me the freedom to aimlessly roam between devices without losing
any progress. I can work on my mac for a bit, then pick up my iPad and resume
my work right then and there. Dropbox far surpasses the ease-of-use of competitors
such as Box.com, and its native Mac application is far less intrusive, as well.</p>

<h3>Google+ (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google+/id447119634?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>I&#8217;m a social media weirdo. I have to try out every one that comes along. I even
tried out <a href="http://app.net">app.net</a> for a while (I still have an account there).
I started using this app far more after the amazing redesign which happened
right around Christmastime. It was indeed an enjoyable occasion. I use G+ to stay
in contact with friends who now work at Google and with friends of mine who insist
on Google-only living: an Android phone, Google+ to communicate (Messenger), and
Google Docs to collaborate.</p>

<h3>Google Chrome (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/chrome/id535886823?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en/chrome/browser/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Chrome on Mac is absolutely awesome. I use it obsessively.</p>

<p>Chrome on the iPhone is something I had to warm up to a bit more. It behaves far
differently than Safari on iOS and the controls are in completely different places.
After some adjustment, I&#8217;ve come to appreciate its incredible flexibility and
strength in the mobile realm.</p>

<h3>Google Maps (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google-maps/id585027354?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>Apple Maps has yet to lead me to a hospital that isn&#8217;t there, or on a road that has
been demolished, but I still missed the Google Maps speed and accuracy. I have also
found that Google Maps is far better for finding nearby amenities, such as coffee,
gas, and food.</p>

<h3>Google Translate (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google-translate/id414706506?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>While I am relatively proficient in the language, learning German is a process.
I have found this app very helpful during my studies and even when having a
causal conversation over Skype in German.</p>

<h3>Gmail (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/gmail-email-from-google/id422689480?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>As with G+ above, the redesign really did it for me. It was, all of a sudden,
a reliable, beautiful, and agile experience, to use this app. It was incredibly
buggy before (it seemed to be a product from Google&#8217;s insistence that online
mobile apps will be dominant, over native apps), but it has come a long way.</p>

<h3>iA Writer (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ia-writer/id392502056?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ia-writer/id439623248?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Whenever I have a thought that I want to remember and ponder later, I write it
down in a note. This usually happens while I am on-the-go. I will then come
back later and review my thoughts and ideas in iA Writer for Mac. I am so thankful
that iA Writer offers syncing through services like iCloud and Dropbox.</p>

<p>I have even been known to write essays on my iPhone of 1000+ words while I walk
between classes, to dinner in Collegetown, and to and from rehearsals. Two of the
three &#8220;A&#8221; papers I wrote last year (one writes few papers when studying engineering)
were written almost entirely in iA Writer for iOS.</p>

<h3>Instapaper (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/instapaper/id288545208?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>After much consideration, I decided to include this app on my list. I have used
Instapaper for many years now, and have truly enjoyed using it. It has,
unforunately, become a repository for articles I&#8217;d like to read, but probably
never will. I found Instapaper very useful, however, to pass the time during
long plane/car/bus rides, as well as long layovers between flights.</p>

<h3>iTerm2 (<a href="http://www.iterm2.com/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Almost all of my development before May this year was done in Terminal.app.
While I have appreciated its service, I decided to move on to iTerm2 upon a
recommendation from a friend. iTerm2 is light and doesn&#8217;t have any weird &#8220;Mac
baggage&#8221; which Terminal.app does. It&#8217;s simple to configure (though there are
far too many configuration options, in my opinion), and easy to use.</p>

<h3>Lightroom 4 (<a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/photoshop-lightroom.html">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>When I first got my Mac, I bought Apple&#8217;s Aperture to handle photo editing and
management. When Lightroom 1 came out, I gave it a try and really enjoyed how
lightweight it felt. It&#8217;s incredibly easy to use, and its catalogs are quite
small, relative to Aperture&#8217;s. It is easily extendible, with custom plugins
for exporting photos and custom presets for one-click photo editing. I&#8217;ve since
stayed with Lightroom, and never looked back.</p>

<h3>Netflix (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/netflix/id363590051?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>I have a slight obsession with Star Trek: The Next Generation, and, more
recently, with Star Trek: Voyager. Netflix has been a wonderful means of
distraction when I need to escape to the twenty-fourth century for some R &amp; R.</p>

<h3>Pages (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pages/id361309726?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pages/id409201541?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Pages is similar to iA Writer, but built for presentation-geared reports and
papers. If the formatting matters, Pages is there to save the day. I wrote quite
a few lab reports on Pages for iOS.</p>

<h3>Paper (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pages/id361309726?mt=8">iPad</a>)</h3>

<p>Paper by FiftyThree is pretty freakin&#8217; awesome. It&#8217;s incredibly agile, and very
robust. While I am no artist, it&#8217;s great for drawing up a quick website mock-up
and sending it off to colleagues. I am still in search of the right stylus, however
&mdash; I am using the Bamboo stylus from Wacom, but I need a tip which has more
precision for use with Paper. Let me know if you know of one I should pick up.</p>

<h3>Sparrow (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sparrow/id492573565?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sparrow/id417250177?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>I have been using Sparrow since its private beta days, and I just love the thing.
Sparrow for Mac is a beaut&#8217; and Sparrow for iOS makes managing my Gmail accounts
so easy and painless, it&#8217;s almost too good to be true.</p>

<h3>Spotify (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/spotify/id324684580?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="http://www.spotify.com/us/download/mac/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Unfortunately, I am not made of money, and my bank account resembles that which
one might expect of a poor college student. In my hopes to spend less on music,
I signed up for Spotify and have just loved it. I have discovered several new
artists that I have come to adore (can it get better than some Babyface or Marc
Broussard??), and for that, I am thankful. Spotify for iOS is a bit weird when
trying to initialize radio on a 3G connection, but it&#8217;s something I am willing
to live with for the time being.</p>

<h3>TextMate 2 Alpha (<a href="http://blog.macromates.com/2011/textmate-2-0-alpha/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>As I mentioned above, I code endlessly. My trusty companion is TextMate 2. In 2006,
<a href="http://blog.dcxn.com">Nick Rowe</a> showed me what would become the text editor to
change my world. After learning all the key bindings, it was hard to switch when
I started learning more about vim. So I stuck with TextMate. When TextMate 2 Alpha
came out, I was never happier. Rebuilt from the ground up, it has all the memory
management I could have hoped for out of TextMate 1. I love this app with all of
my heart.</p>

<h3>Things 2 (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/spotify/id324684580?mt=8">iPhone</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/things/id407951449?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Pretty much the only reason I&#8217;ve been productive this year is due to Things.
I was a beta tester for Things Cloud and Things 2 (both Mac and iOS) and was
delighted to find that this task-management application suite so quickly synced
all of my tasks, and <em>never</em> failed. I&#8217;ve never lost anything with Things Cloud,
and that reliability is important, when it means the difference between getting
someting done, and forgetting about it.</p>

<h3>TuneIn Radio (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tunein-radio-pro-listen-to/id319295332?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>The BBC World Service News station is one that I have grown to love, many thanks
to TuneIn Radio. It gives the user the opportunity to listen to radio stations
being broadcast all around the world &mdash; even in different languages. I have
learned a great deal of German, listening to Deutsche-Welle Nachrichten in this
app. It works beautifully over 3G, too, which makes long car rides all the more
pleasant.</p>

<h3>Tweetbot for (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter-iphone/id428851691?mt=8">iPhone</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter-ipad/id498801050?mt=8">iPad</a>, and <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter/id557168941?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Last, but certainly not least, I must acknowledge my addiction to Twitter. When
I wake in the morning, I never fail to reach over, grab my iPhone, check my email,
then check my Twitter feed. It usually takes a long breakfast to get through
all of them, but I am able to change devices, due to syncing of my position via
Tweet Marker. Before Tweetbot, I used Twitter for iPhone 3.5.1 (before that horrid
redesign), but really wanted CloudApp support. Tweetbot was the natural alternative
and everyone raved about it. After a couple weeks of using Tweetbot on a daily
basis, I deleted Twitter for iPhone without hesitation. Tweetbot is the best
way to interface with Twitter on any Apple device.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Immediate Future of Jekyll]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/18/the-immediate-future-of-jekyll/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T18:33:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/18/the-immediate-future-of-jekyll</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> is a static blog generator created by <a href="https://github.com/mojombo">Tom Preston-Werner</a>, the
current CEO of <a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a> and one of GitHub&#8217;s co-founders, and by <a href="https://github.com/qrush">Nick Quaranto</a>,
who is now at 37signals. Jekyll is <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Sites">pretty freakin&#8217; popular</a> and it&#8217;s
also the engine that drives <a href="http://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>.</p>

<p>After an hour-long chat with Tom, I&#8217;m optimistic about the future of Jekyll. He&#8217;s
really excited about where it&#8217;s headed and has a vision in mind about what he&#8217;d
like it to become.
Here&#8217;s what we ironed out during our conversation:</p>

<p>Led by Tom, a Jekyll development team, of which I&#8217;m the first recruit, will
be tackling the problems with Jekyll and continuously improving its functionality
and ease-of-use. The focus will remain on making a tool that allows one to easily
create and manage a static blog.</p>

<p>Suuuper basic (unofficial) design principles:</p>

<ol>
<li>Keep it simple</li>
<li>Easy to extend</li>
<li>Solid safe mode (for GitHub Pages)</li>
</ol>


<p>What we need to tackle:</p>

<ol>
<li>Fix bugs (!!)</li>
<li>Decrease build time (!!)</li>
<li>Docs for site</li>
<li>TomDoc everything</li>
<li>Release new site</li>
<li>Finish same site generator</li>
<li>Include some faster LSI</li>
</ol>


<p>Want to help? Check out the <a href="http://git.io/jekyll-discussion">discussion label</a> and add in your two cents.<br>
Want to contribute code? Check out the <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/issues">issues</a> and submit a pull request with
a fix.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m really excited about the immediate future of Jekyll and what it will become
in the next 6 months or so and the dev team takes on the issues outlined above.
I hope you&#8217;re as excited as we are to get this project back on its feet.</p>

<p>If you want to chat more or have any questions, you know <a href="http://twitter.com/parkr">where to find me</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Email Notifications in Web Apps]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/12/email-notifications-in-web-apps/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-12T02:05:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/12/email-notifications-in-web-apps</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Email notifications from web apps have been annoying us for months now. Ever since Twitter, Facebook and other notification-heavy apps began automatically sending notifications to us (alas, without our consent), public opinion seems to have developed a hatred for email notifications. But, I implore you, understand the flipside:</p>

<div class='embed tweet'><blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="de"><p>I really don’t need your web service to keep another inbox of messages and notifications for me.</p>&mdash; Marco Arment (@marcoarment) <a href="https://twitter.com/marcoarment/status/278705209507721217">12. Dezember 2012</a></blockquote>
<script async src="http://blog.parkermoore.de//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script></div>


<p>Email notifications in web apps is a way of unifying one&#8217;s virtual &#8220;inbox&#8221;. Dealing with too many is overwhelming.</p>

<p>Keep email notifications around.</p>

<p>(But, for pete&#8217;s sake, <em>ask</em> your users whether they want email notifications before you activate them for their accounts.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Letter to Tom Preston-Werner]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T17:03:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m a huge advocate of static site generators and have always favoured <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> as my go-to static site generator.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, it&#8217;s fallen out of active development. I&#8217;ve been trying to contact Tom Preston-Werner (<a href="https://github.com/mojombo">@mojombo</a>) about it, but so far: nothing. (To be fair, I have gotten two replies, but they were not productive other than saying that he was looking for new maintainers. That was May 2012.)</p>

<p>So here&#8217;s my open letter to you, Tom, about saving   Jekyll from open-source oblivion.</p>

<blockquote><p>Tom,</p>

<p>Hope you had a pleasant weekend.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s what I wish to see happen with Jekyll:</p>

<ol>
<li>Start an Org on Github and move the Jekyll repo to that org</li>
<li>Add several maintainers to that org (I&#8217;d be happy to help out as a maintainer!)</li>
<li>Add another author or two to the Jekyll gem so that we can gem push and release new versions.</li>
<li>Give at least one other person access to push to the source of jekyllrb.com so that the docs can be updated</li>
</ol>


<p>Problem I&#8217;m trying to solve:</p>

<blockquote><p>Jekyll is incredibly popular and is an incredibly powerful tool, but is not being actively maintained centrally, so though the world around it is evolving, it is staying stagnant and plagued by the same issues it has been for the last four years.</p></blockquote>

<p>Solution:</p>

<blockquote><p>Add maintainers to Jekyll to help deal with issues, push new versions, and update the documentation when you don&#8217;t have the time.</p></blockquote>

<p>The great thing about version control systems is that changes can always be reverted.</p>

<p>Thanks in advance for your attention to this problem and willingness to help it continue growing.</p>

<p>Warm Regards,<br>
Parker Moore</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iA Writer Needs Print Configuration]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/ia-writer-needs-print-configuration/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T16:41:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/ia-writer-needs-print-configuration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have really adored iA Writer and use the app obsessively on my iPhone, iPad and Mac. It&#8217;s arguably one of my most oft-used apps. I write all sorts of things with the app: blog posts/ideas (like this one), essays, lab reports &#8211; even the occasional code snippet. It&#8217;s my writing tool of choice, and I thank Information Architects for writing such an awesome app.</p>

<p>I also print out a lot of my writing. I like to edit by hand with a pen and paper. I like the beautiful typeface that iA Writer provides and the margins on 8.5&#8221; x 11&#8221; paper (US) are amazing. I&#8217;ve really enjoyed the almost typewriter-like essence of the print-outs which iA Writer provides.</p>

<p>I&#8217;d really love some more configuration options for printing, however. While I will undoubtedly hear the argument that iA Writer offers no configuration <em>on purpose</em>, I will argue that the &#8220;No Configuration Rule&#8221; must only apply to in-app writing, not to the manifestation of this writing in paper form.</p>

<p>The No Configuration Rule is supported by the fact that configuration and modification of the working environment is often a hindrance to one&#8217;s ability to write awesome content. It&#8217;s a distraction. But it&#8217;s a distraction only when <em>writing</em>, not when printing. I&#8217;d say this No Configuration Rule thus can only be justified for writing, i.e. on;y be justified for the look and feel of the writing experience in the app.</p>

<p>But that&#8217;s an argument with too many implications. Let&#8217;s make it a bit smaller, to the size of a wish:</p>

<p>My only real wish for this app is to allow double-spaced print-outs. That&#8217;s it. I want to be able to edit my papers double-spaced.</p>

<p>So what say you, Information Architects? Think it&#8217;s possible? I&#8217;d really appreciate it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Brief Adventure]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/11/30/a-brief-adventure/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-30T21:23:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/11/30/a-brief-adventure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve decided to take next semester off (Spring 2013) to pursue an internship at <a href="http://6wunderkinder.com">6Wunderkinder</a> in Berlin, Germany. I&#8217;ll be starting work at the end of January and returning to the U.S. around the middle of August. I&#8217;m very excited that 6Wunderkinder extended their offer for an internship to me and were down with a 6-7 month internship. I&#8217;m pumped to be working with such awesome web and app devs.</p>

<p>So how did this happen? It&#8217;s a long story that I&#8217;ll talk about later, but for now I&#8217;ll give you the abridged version.</p>

<p>In the bleak winter of 2011, I emailed 6W about the possibility of a 3-month summer internship (May, June, July) in 2013. They replied very kindly, basically saying that it was way too early to say whether that was a possibility.</p>

<p>This Fall, I sent them a follow-up email asking if they were still interested. They replied saying that it was a definite possibility and asked that I send along some projects I had worked on. After reviewing my email &#8220;project resume&#8221;, they offered me an interview. Thanksgiving morning, I woke up bright and early to meet Ben on Skype. Great fun, and got to meet Isaac and Alex of the 6W API team, too. Ben followed up with an email offering a second interview.</p>

<p>During the time between the first and second interviews, I decided that I needed a break from my studies - Cornell is a particularly rigorous place and has a tendency to be demoralizing. So it was time for a break so that I could return in the Fall with new energy and vigor. I shot Ben an email indicating my interest in starting to work for them as early as the end of January, and to my surprise, were very interested in having me earlier.</p>

<p>During the second interview, I talked with Isaac and Ben more about what my role at 6Wunderkinder would be and how life in Berlin would look for me. All seemed really cool. When Ben officially made the offer to have me as an intern, I gladly accepted and we discussed logistics.</p>

<p>So there it is! It&#8217;s amazing what an email can do nowadays when you have congruent interests and a cool, responsive company like 6W.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m going to really miss <a href="http://theclassnotes.com">The Class Notes</a>, the <a href="http://gleeclub.com">Glee Club</a> (no, not like the show &#8220;Glee&#8221;), and my other friends here, and the ease of college life. That being said, I&#8217;m really grateful for this amazing opportunity abroad with a one-of-a-kind start-up like 6W.</p>

<p>Many thanks to Ben Braun, Isaac Wolkerstorfer, Alex Koppel, and the whole 6Wunderkinder team for giving me the opportunity. Thanks, guys!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Israel &amp; Hamas]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/11/16/israel-and-hamas/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T18:12:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/11/16/israel-and-hamas</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You may have heard about the recent eruption of violence in Israel and the
Gaza Strip. You may have your opinions set, but just hear me out.</p>

<p>So the way the story goes is that Gaza has been firing lots of rockets
into Israel and Israel has decided to retaliate by firing its own rockets
and otherwise bombarding the Gaza Strip with explosives. So, fire and fire
are at work here.</p>

<p>This is wrong. Hamas (the current leaders of Gaza) is wrong and Israel is
wrong. There is nothing morally justifiable about what either party is doing.</p>

<p>Many have expressed sympathy with Israel and an acquaintance of mine even
posted <a href="">a video produced by the Israel Defense Forces about why it has the
right to retaliate</a> on Facebook. There is absolutely no &#8220;right&#8221; to kill
anyone. No one can justifiably kill anyone else.</p>

<p>Enter: moral excusability. While killing another human being is <em>never</em> morally
justifiable, it is often viewed as morally excusable. That is, it is not
<em>right</em> to kill another human being, but it isn&#8217;t wrong (given the circumstances)
either. Well, that&#8217;s bullshit. If something isn&#8217;t morally justifiable, don&#8217;t do
it.</p>

<p>This eye-for-an-eye thing is getting out of hand. Both parties need to stop
hurting each other and begin discussing what can be done to peacefull coexist.
Unless Israel kills all the Palestinians in the Gaza Strip, there will never
be peace. Unfortunately, it seems like their hawkish Prime Minister, Benjamin
Netanyahu, is just about ready to kill off every non-Israeli in the Gaza Strip.</p>

<p>This whole situation is just despicable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Maintaining Inbox Zero]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/08/06/maintaining-inbox-zero/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-06T00:18:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/08/06/maintaining-inbox-zero</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished up reading <a href="http://mattgemmell.com/2012/08/05/managing-email-realistically/">Matt Gemmell&#8217;s post on email management</a>. If you haven&#8217;t read it, you&#8217;ll want to do make sure you head over to his site and give it a quick read before continuing.</p>

<p>Firstly, I should say that I am a manager, a developer, a web developer and a university student. I get a shit-ton of emails, so don&#8217;t think I don&#8217;t know what I&#8217;m talking about.</p>

<p>Over the years, I have developed an email attack-plan that works well for me, and I think works well for most people I know. This plan entails a seek-and-destroy method of achieving and maintaining Inbox Zero.</p>

<ol>
<li>Have a smartphone. Not only are these things super hip, but they&#8217;re handy as hell for killing off swarms of emails you get throughout the day.</li>
<li>Use your time wisely. Don&#8217;t twiddle your thumbs while on the bus/train/subway on the way to work. Rather, delete the worthless emails and read through the important ones. Re-mark them as unread until you get to the office.</li>
<li>Leverage the full keyboard. After the longest commute you&#8217;ve ever had to make, you&#8217;ve deleted or archived the bogus emails, so now you just have an inbox of awesome emails to go. Spend a half hour to an hour to get back to Inbox Zero. As Matt suggests, read the ones from your friends first &mdash; they&#8217;re always hilarious/useful/intriguing/important.</li>
<li>Go through your work emails after you&#8217;ve had a good laugh. You&#8217;ll be in a better mood when you tell the designer you&#8217;re working with that they&#8217;re crazy and you won&#8217;t come off as such a jerk. Win. Be detailed with these, but be very precise and concise - no one likes a long email.</li>
<li>Next, family. They&#8217;re usually cute and/or stupid. Send a quick reply (&#8220;Cute! Love, Parker&#8221;) and archive. Boom, done.</li>
<li>Resume your daily work. Do <em>not</em>, I repeat, <strong>DO NOT</strong> leave your mail client open. You should work without disturbances. Let them emails come in and sizzle a little in your inbox. If someone needs something absolutely immediately, they&#8217;ll have your phone number and give you a call.</li>
<li>Half an hour before lunch, conduct seek-and-destroy operation burrito sandwich with egg and cheese, i.e. achieve Inbox Zero again. You may want to leave the work emails until later when you&#8217;re not irritable (you&#8217;re hungry, remember?).</li>
<li>Eat lunch and laugh at animals making fools of themselves or watch an inspiring <a href="http://ted.com">TED</a> talk. Resume to work once lunch is over.</li>
<li>Take 5 minutes and reply to those work emails you put off. Resume work.</li>
<li>Half an hour before your work day ends, achieve Inbox Zero again.</li>
<li>Turn off anything on your phone that will remind you that emails exist. No notifications, no automatic push emails, no badge icons. You&#8217;ve left work and now you should spend time with you you care about.</li>
</ol>


<p>Moral of the story: more frequently going through your emails throughout the work day (but in set times that make sense) is the best route. Three is good enough for me on a normal work day, but it&#8217;s more like 45 times during the school year. So many freaking emails.</p>

<p>At the end of the day, forget you have any technology whatsoever, cuddle up with schnookums (your retarded cat) and read a novel. What a great day you just had.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ruby and Rails]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/06/26/ruby-and-rails/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-26T05:38:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/06/26/ruby-and-rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So there&#8217;s been a lot of hype about <a href="http://www.ruby-lang.org/en/">Ruby</a> over the past several years. For those of you who are interested in programming and programming languages, you heard about it right from the start, as its beautiful syntax and ease of use lured many programmers into its use.</p>

<p>While Ruby is wonderful, it wouldn&#8217;t be what it is today without the existence of <a href="http://rubyonrails.org/">Ruby on Rails</a>. This web framework posed the first real threat to PHP. Rails was powerful and agile, and helped web devs create incredbile web apps with incredible ease. The generators that came along with this gem made it possible to get a completely functional website up in a matter of <em>hours</em>, rather than days. That was incredible.</p>

<p>I used Rails on and off, switching between it and CakePHP. I didn&#8217;t really understand Rails&#8217; routes and wanted something like CakePHP&#8217;s <code>bake</code> functionality which creates an entire scaffold with styling and everything. I didn&#8217;t object to the un-RESTful CakePHP nature of using just <code>GET</code> and <code>POST</code> requests, as I didn&#8217;t need the RESTful functionality for any of the sites I was creating. I used Rails for a couple projects, but it always felt like I was coding more than was necessary.</p>

<p>I started working at <a href="http://www.thinktopography.com">Think Topography</a> this summer and was tasked with building the new <a href="http://www.ithacahours.com">Ithaca Hours</a> mobile web app that would facilitate the use of Ithaca Hours. My boss had always used Rails and suggested that I use Rails for the API end of this project. It seemed like the best choice, given the requirements of the project, and so it began: I dove back into Rails.</p>

<p>Once I wrapped my head around routes and the devise/warden authentication framework, I was truckin&#8217;. I was making huge progress on this API and learning gobs of information along the way. I was loving Rails and appreciating its incredible power. I was writing tests in rspec, which was a joy when combined with factory_girl.</p>

<p>I recently worked on a project for <a href="https://www.mhusa.com/contact-tools/login.asp?c">Moët &amp; Chandon USA</a> that was built upon the CakePHP framework, and I was not nearly as excited about returning to this framework as I expected to be, given my incredible comfort with the language and the framework.</p>

<p>But my work at Think Topography has changed me &#8211; I&#8217;m a Rails guy for sure.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncomfortable]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/06/03/uncomfortable/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-03T17:10:34+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/06/03/uncomfortable</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Members of the Cornell University Glee Club and Chorus were asked to perform at a wedding on campus yesterday, and as a member of the Glee Club, I volunteered to sing. This wedding, being a Catholic one, was quite traditional, and left me feeling quite uneasy about my participation in the ceremony.</p>

<p>I have renounced any belief in the Judeo-Christian God for about 8 years. I grew up in an Episcopalian church in Rochester, NY and it was quite a liberal experience. Though I appreciate what religion can do for many around the world, I find it stifling, and often quite demeaning. As I listened to the prayers, I was overwhelmed by a feeling of unease. Questions filled my head: <em>How can anyone subject themselves to complete obedience to something of which they know so little? How can anyone find this comforting, to relinquish control to some &#8220;being&#8221; that most likely does not exist? Why do members of our society, despite incredible evidence against it, continue to believe in such an archaic set of beliefs?</em></p>

<p>I found myself wishing I could get up and leave. My heart began to race, fueled by the &#8220;fight-or-flight&#8221; instinct. I felt threatened, not only personally, but also I felt a threat to our entire society. We see, on a practically <em>daily</em> basis, how the Abrahamic religions are holding us back in many different ways. We are paralyzed by our fear that disbelief will mean condemnation, but all forget that the concepts of hell and purgatory are Medieval conceptions fabricated by the Roman Catholic Church to provoke incredible fear. These conceptions are just as despicable, just as reprehensible, as the tithe. These conceptions invoke a fear that is very real, but it has been seen time and time again that obedience caused by means of fear always falls.</p>

<p>There is hope. The population of &#8220;non-believers&#8221;, those who do not profess a belief in the God of Abraham, is growing rapidly. With the ability of science to definitively answer questions that were historically answered by religious doctrines, we are able to let our belief in the Judeo-Christian God go. We no longer need a priest, an imam or a rabbi to interpret the scriptures for us &mdash; we have scientists that can do this for us! Our scientists, their theories based upon facts (things we <em>know</em> to be true, not just a guess or a belief), have given us verifiable beliefs. Skepticism is welcomed. It is a wonderful thing to be a part of the scientific world!</p>

<p>Listening to the prayers professing ultimate devotion to some being no one actually knows, I became uneasy. Our society can do better than this. We must be determined to live in a more fact-based society… <em>we must</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thank my lucky stars]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/05/30/thank-my-lucky-stars/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/05/30/thank-my-lucky-stars</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night, I experienced the most significant car trouble that has ever occurred while I was driving. As I and a couple friends were leaving the city of Rochester for home in our respective suburbs, I ran over a pothole that was quite large (it is Spring in a city which experiences incredible snowfall, so they are to be expected) and heard a thud and a &#8220;whooooosshhh&#8221;. I stopped the car.</p>

<p>I hopped out of the driver&#8217;s seat and inspected the vehicle. My front left tire had popped and I was now riding on the rim. No good. I turn off the car and switch into crisis mode. <em>I&#8217;ve done this before</em>, I think as I remember back to helping my father change the tire on the back of our minivan a year or so ago. The other guys in the car behind me (we had two cars, luckily) hop out to help. I grab the spare tire, jack and wrench from the trunk and begin the process. <em>Loosen the bolts. Jack up the car. Take out the bolts. Replace the tire with the spare. Reattach the bolts. Put the car back on the ground. Tighten the bolts.</em></p>

<p>As we are working on the car, we realize that the car is not on flat terrain. The road upon which we&#8217;ve stopped is an incline. We jack up the car with incredible trepidation, with two guys on the lower end of the car, applying pressure to ensure that there are no issues with the car falling from the jack and ruining the axle.</p>

<p>All goes as planned and we lower the car. Once the car is on the ground, we notice that the spare is flat! Jeebus, this is annoying. Bereft of a pump or any other way of putting air into the tire, we&#8217;re stuck. I finally cave and call AAA, only to find that I&#8217;m not on the plan and that &#8220;the plan covers [my father], not the vehicle.&#8221; After about 15 minutes of calls (it&#8217;s easily 12:15AM by this point), my father sorts it out and is able to convince AAA to add me to the plan. They give me a call and I&#8217;m (finally) able to request a tow truck. Whew, that was annoying.</p>

<p>All while I&#8217;m on the phone with AAA, I suggest to the other car that they head out (a couple of them had to wake up very early). They agree and go to leave, only to find that their car won&#8217;t start. Now this is quite a turn of events. Two cars, out-of-commision on the highway very late at night &mdash; this is how horror films start.</p>

<p>As we&#8217;re waiting for the tow truck to arrive, a friend and I are talking while keeping a look out. We see a tow truck drive by and we flag him down, but he&#8217;s not the tow truck which was called for us. A kind-hearted guy, he agrees to help us out. He maneauvers his vehicle over to where my car was disabled and inspects the spare. He pumps it up and determines that it&#8217;s not leaking! What joy! One car back to road-readiness.</p>

<p>The other tow truck arrives as we&#8217;re working to blow up my tire and he
jumps the other vehicle. All is well.</p>

<p>Couldn&#8217;t have asked to deal with this with better people. Was so glad
they were there to help. Thank my lucky stars.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
