<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: religion | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/religion/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-23T15:47:52-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Rid of Senate Prayer]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/09/get-rid-of-senate-prayer/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T18:17:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/09/get-rid-of-senate-prayer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier today, I was watching a <a href="http://www.c-spanvideo.org/program/SenateSession4967">C-SPAN video</a> of a U.S. Senate session on
February 1, 2012. This was the first time I had ever watched a Senate session
from the beginning and, to my surprise, they began with a prayer.</p>

<p>Hold up. A prayer? In a session of one of our government&#39;s highest legislative
bodies?! I suppose I shouldn&#39;t be too surprised, what with the (often crazy)
Religious Right getting after the government with Bible-backed policies and
all. It was nevertheless astonishing to see the institutionalization of religion
in our government.</p>

<p>I generally like our government, but this changes everything. Man, I was angry.
I felt betrayed and undermined - like I was worth nothing to anyone in D.C.</p>

<p>So I wrote to my senators:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Dear Senator,</p>

<p>I wish to ask for the Senator&#39;s thoughts on the opening prayer which begins a
Senate session. I have done my research and see that this prayer has been a
part of Senate procedure since 1789 and was recommended by Benjamin Franklin
about two years previous, but I question its place in our secular government.
It is, frankly, inappropriate that any governmental body in our United States
of America be so closely tied to one religious creed in a nation with many
hundreds and thousands of religious belief systems. I will not deny that
religion is a part of politics - a belief in a certain religious creed often
results in an election win - but it has absolutely no place in governance.
It is insulting to think that any one religion is given special treatment in
our governments.</p>

<p>I ask the Senator to introduce a bill which will put an end to this Senate
Prayer, for, while Mr. Franklin may have been right in 1789, he is most
certainly wrong now. We have moved past a blind reliance on God, and it is,
now more than ever, a hindrance on our Great Government.
God&#39;s interference in our government has forced limited civil rights for
minorities, was a rationale for slavery, and is still fighting against a
Woman&#39;s Right to Choose, a Citizen&#39;s Right To Marry Whomever He or She Wishes,
Scientific Advancement in many fields and so on.</p>

<p>It is our imperative as citizens to think of each other first and to respect
the different viewpoints and beliefs of our fellow Americans. Honoring any
religion on our Senate floor is a betrayal of this principle, and it must be
stopped.</p>

<p>Thank you,<br />
Parker Moore<br />
Constituent</p>
</blockquote>

<p>If you care about religious freedom at all, I would urge you to do the same.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Afterlife?]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/30/an-afterlife/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-30T19:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/30/an-afterlife</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am not a religious man, yet I find myself curious about the prospect of an afterlife. Is
there something beyond this life, in this dimension, in this universe? While I don&#39;t believe
in the traditional conception of an afterlife (one&#39;s soul ascends to a blissful place, where
it inhabits all space and time for eternity), I do like to think we live on beyond the
time we take our last breath.</p>

<p>In ninth grade, I graduated to a Sunday School class which resembled a forum &mdash;
discussion-based learning. A retired history teacher, a Public Defender, and a social
worker led the discussions in this class. The dialogue probed our most deeply held beliefs
and asked profound questions about  life, spirituality, goodness, happiness, beauty, and
other similar topics.</p>

<p>One day, we were discussing the afterlife. The normal answers dominated the conversation:
&quot;When one dies, one&#39;s soul ascends into Heaven to be with one&#39;s family members and with
God,&quot; and &quot;We exist everywhere and with everyone. We watch over those we love and help
them live good lives.&quot; When the question came to me, I wasn&#39;t sure how to respond. Can an
atheist believe in an afterlife? If so, did I?</p>

<p>I hadn&#39;t given it much thought before, but I pondered it for a moment and concluded, &quot;An
individual&#39;s afterlife is the culmination of the memories others have of the individual.
It is the legacy that individual leaves behind and the impact that individual had on those
he or she encountered.&quot;</p>

<p>The more I thought about it, the more it made sense. If we don&#39;t have souls, how do we
explain this legacy of the afterlife concretely? The afterlife is not something experienced
by the deceased individual, but by everyone else he or she impacted.</p>

<p>Surround your pullquote like this {" text to be quoted "}</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
