<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: feature-requests | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/feature-requests/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-04T10:56:19-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iA Writer Needs Print Configuration]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/ia-writer-needs-print-configuration/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T16:41:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/ia-writer-needs-print-configuration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have really adored iA Writer and use the app obsessively on my iPhone, iPad and Mac. It's arguably one of my most oft-used apps. I write all sorts of things with the app: blog posts/ideas (like this one), essays, lab reports -- even the occasional code snippet. It's my writing tool of choice, and I thank Information Architects for writing such an awesome app.</p>

<p>I also print out a lot of my writing. I like to edit by hand with a pen and paper. I like the beautiful typeface that iA Writer provides and the margins on 8.5" x 11" paper (US) are amazing. I've really enjoyed the almost typewriter-like essence of the print-outs which iA Writer provides.</p>

<p>I'd really love some more configuration options for printing, however. While I will undoubtedly hear the argument that iA Writer offers no configuration <em>on purpose</em>, I will argue that the "No Configuration Rule" must only apply to in-app writing, not to the manifestation of this writing in paper form.</p>

<p>The No Configuration Rule is supported by the fact that configuration and modification of the working environment is often a hindrance to one's ability to write awesome content. It's a distraction. But it's a distraction only when <em>writing</em>, not when printing. I'd say this No Configuration Rule thus can only be justified for writing, i.e. on;y be justified for the look and feel of the writing experience in the app.</p>

<p>But that's an argument with too many implications. Let's make it a bit smaller, to the size of a wish:</p>

<p>My only real wish for this app is to allow double-spaced print-outs. That's it. I want to be able to edit my papers double-spaced.</p>

<p>So what say you, Information Architects? Think it's possible? I'd really appreciate it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
