<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: jekyll | Hey, I’m Parker.]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/categories/jekyll/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-17T00:34:09-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Clearing Up Confusion Around baseurl]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2014/04/27/clearing-up-confusion-around-baseurl/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-27T16:52:54-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2014/04/27/clearing-up-confusion-around-baseurl</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>TL;DR: Don&#39;t use baseurl. It&#39;ll drive you crazy.</strong></p>

<p>Hey, so there&#39;s been a bit of confusion about what the Jekyll configuration
option called <code>baseurl</code> is. Part of the beauty of open-source and of Jekyll
is that there&#39;s a lot of flexibility. Unfortunately, much of this
flexibility doesn&#39;t apply to <code>baseurl</code>. Here&#39;s a quick distillation of its
intentions, and how to use it.</p>

<h2>Mimic GitHub Pages</h2>

<p><code>baseurl</code> was <a href="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll/commit/4a8fc1fa6e3fa5dc05c81ac5ac4ffed0b0818ac4">originally added back in 2010</a> to allow
&quot;the user to test the website with the internal webserver under the same
base url it will be deployed to on a production server&quot;.<sup id="fnref1"><a href="#fn1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup> </p>

<h2>Example</h2>

<p>So let&#39;s say I come up with a cool new project. I want to make
documentation for a project I&#39;m working on called &quot;ubiqity&quot;, and I&#39;ll be
deploying it to GitHub Pages as a repo under my username, &quot;@parkr&quot;. Its
documentation will be available at the URL <code>http://parkr.github.io/ubiquity</code>.</p>

<p>In this example, the term &quot;base URL&quot; refers to <code>ubiquity</code>. When I go to
develop my website, I can set the <code>baseurl</code> key to equal <code>ubiquity</code> and
navigate my website from <code>http://localhost:4000/ubiquity/</code>, as though it
were hosted on GitHub Pages. Notice that the only difference here between
development and production is the host: <code>parkr.github.io</code> vs.
<code>localhost:4000</code>.<sup id="fnref2"><a href="#fn2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<h2>Configuring Your Site Properly</h2>

<ol>
<li>Set <code>baseurl</code> in your <code>_config.yml</code> to match the production URL without
the host (e.g. <code>ubiquity</code>, <em>not</em> <code>http://parkr.github.io/ubiquity</code>).</li>
<li>Run <code>jekyll serve -w</code> and go to <code>http://localhost:4000/your_baseurl/</code>,
replacing <code>your_baseurl</code> with whatever you set <code>baseurl</code> to in your
<code>_config.yml</code>, and not forgetting the trailing slash.</li>
<li>Make sure everything works. Feel free to prepend your urls with
<code>site.baseurl</code>.</li>
<li>Push up to your host and see that everything works there, too!</li>
</ol>

<h2>Success!</h2>

<p>You&#39;ve done it! You&#39;ve successfully used <code>baseurl</code> and the world is
wonderful.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
<hr>
<ol>

<li id="fn1">
<p>https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll/pull/235&nbsp;<a href="#fnref1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>

<li id="fn2">
<p>The port also differs, but that&#39;s not what&#39;s important here. The point is that everything after the <code>/</code> after the host is the same.&nbsp;<a href="#fnref2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p>
</li>

</ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking Over Someone Else's Open-Source Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/11/04/taking-over-someone-elses-open-source-project/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-04T21:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/11/04/taking-over-someone-elses-open-source-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last December (2012), <a href="http://tom.preston-werner.com">Tom Preston-Werner</a> granted me <a href="/images/mojombo-added-parkr-to-jekyll.png">push &amp; pull access to
mojombo/jekyll</a>. I had written a <a href="/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner/">letter to Tom about the future of Jekyll</a>
and after a bit of persistence on my part, he relented:</p>

<p><img src="/images/mojombo-added-parkr-to-jekyll.png" alt="mojombo added parkr to mojombo/jekyll"></p>

<p>After a somewhat lengthy (and <a href="/images/jekyll-shall-inherit-the-earth.png">amusing</a>) conversation via Skype, I knew what
Tom&#39;s priorities were for the project and where I could help. I started off
trimming down the number of open issues. At the time, they numbered just over 300.
After a quick visit to Buffalo to tackle some issues with <a href="http://quaran.to">Nick Quaranto</a> at a
Buffalo <a href="http://openhack.github.io">OpenHack</a> meetup at <a href="http://coworkbuffalo.com">CoworkBuffalo</a>, we were down to fewer than 200
open issues. I continued to work through them (much to my parents&#39; dismay) all
through Winter Break. I was making good progress in the triage process: I knew
what many of the problems were with v0.12.1 and was formulating ideas about how
we might go about fixing them.</p>

<p><img src="/images/jekyll-shall-inherit-the-earth.png" alt="jekyll shall inherit the earth"></p>

<p>In January, I flew out to San Francisco to visit my sister for a week. I setup a
meeting with Tom to talk more about Jekyll and a plan for moving forward to a
v1.0.0 release. After about an hour or so at GitHub&#39;s office in SoMa, talking
through various PR&#39;s, Tom said I could start merging pull requests.</p>

<p>Consultation with Tom was challenging (he runs a multi-million dollar company
after all), as it was increasingly difficult for him to find time for Jekyll.
Despite <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/issues/578#issuecomment-11414645">announcing that he was going to commit some of his &quot;20% time&quot; to Jekyll</a>,
he eventually abandoned that as impractical. As time went on, I received fewer
replies to my emails and eventually stopped sending anything that didn&#39;t
absolutely <em>require</em> Tom&#39;s input.</p>

<p>In March, I knew I needed more help. Tom wasn&#39;t able to give much time and I
was trying to tackle this project alone. I had noticed that <a href="http://mattr.info">Matt Rogers</a>
shared my vision for Jekyll, so I asked Tom to add him on as a contributor to
the repo. By v1.0.3, he had started merging pull requests like a BAW$ and was
the sanity to my ridiculously-obsessed, inexperienced mind. Since Matt joined, I
haven&#39;t really heard much from Tom. I write the occasional email and get the
occasional reply but he&#39;s essentially phased out of the normal development of
Jekyll. Matt &amp; I have essentially taken over the project altogether.</p>

<p>By May, we were ready to ship v1.0.0. With the help of all the amazing
contributors, Matt, and my many mentors along the way, I finally ran
<code>rake release</code> for 1.0. The project was ours.</p>

<p>Since realizing that this product has few constraints outside of those I&#39;ve
constructed for it in my mind (no one is going to tell me, &quot;No, you may not
implement that feature or add that enhancement&quot; without a valid argument as to
my solution&#39;s invalidity), I&#39;ve been thinking about what it means to take over
someone else&#39;s project. <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/commit/d189e05d236769c1e5594af9db4d6eacb86fc16e">Jekyll is 5 years old.</a> I wasn&#39;t there in 2008 when
it was first born as <code>autoblog</code>. Jekyll has changed a lot, as has its vision and
purpose. It&#39;s used by lots of people now, whether via <a href="http://pages.github.com">GitHub Pages</a> or
locally.</p>

<p>Taking over someone else&#39;s project takes a deep understanding of what the
project is and what it should be. As much as I wish Jekyll could make me
kräuterquark, that&#39;s outside the scope of the project. Developing that lens is
crucial when taking over someone else&#39;s project.</p>

<p>Mentoring on the part of the original owner/previous maintainer(s) is
exceedingly significant in the development of this critical lens. I am so
grateful that I was able to meet up with Tom back in January and to have some
amount of input from him as I understood what the project should be.</p>

<p>It would be ill-advised to take over someone else&#39;s project without a partner.
Once Matt joined the team, Tom was able to step back into a much lesser role.
If I had tried to do what I did without any guidance (or at least sanity
checks), Jekyll v1.0.0 would have been a complete shit-show.</p>

<p>Trust in the community must also be earned. If people highly doubted my ability
to handle Jekyll, Tom would have likely removed me and found a replacement. I
argued a lot and got into some pretty heated debates at the beginning. There
were a couple people who didn&#39;t share the vision that I had inherited from Tom
and stopped contributing to the project altogether. I feel like we now have a
pretty great community around Jekyll and are able to help each other out and
share cool plugins and sites that we made for/with Jekyll.</p>

<p>Taking over someone else&#39;s open-source project was new terrain for me in
December, and still is today. It can be successful with the right amount of
mentoring and gradual removal of trusted feedback by the previous maintainer(s).</p>

<p>With some old projects that are brought back to life by the passing of the
torch, the new maintainers are able to experience the added bonus of feeling
like Frankenstein, which, I will say, is a pretty cool feeling.</p>

<p><img src="/images/it-lives.jpg" alt="igor"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jekyll 1.0 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T00:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I&#39;m proud to announce the release of Jekyll 1.0. There are a million
goodies and fixes to enjoy, and we&#39;re (the still-active Jekyll core team
members: Tom, Matt and I) really excited to share this first major release
with you. Be sure to follow <a href="http://twitter.com/jekyllrb">@jekyllrb</a> for
updates on future releases and links to cool plugins.</p>

<p>Some quick highlights:</p>

<ul>
<li>New subcommands: new, build, serve, and import</li>
<li>Amazing new docs at http://jekyllrb.com (thanks to @cobyism)</li>
<li><code>jekyll new</code> creates a new scaffold so you can get blogging even faster</li>
<li>Drafts, i.e. posts without dates</li>
<li>New &quot;excerpt&quot; feature on posts</li>
<li>Timezone configuration</li>
<li>&#39;gist&#39; liquid tag</li>
<li>Source directory protection</li>
</ul>

<p>... and <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/v1.0.0/History.txt">so much more</a>!</p>

<p>We also have an <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/upgrading/">Upgrading</a> page that clarifies
some breaking changes and tips for upgrading to Jekyll 1.0.</p>

<p>As many of you know, Jekyll lay mostly stagnant for quite some time. At 0.11.2 and
0.12.0, it was pretty stable. It had some annoying bugs, but nothing much that
couldn&#39;t be worked around or monkey-patched.</p>

<p>After using Jekyll last summer to help build
<a href="http://cals.cornell.edu">Cornell&#39;s College of Agriculture and Life Sciences website</a>,
I took a renewed interest in seeing this project move forward. Last December,
Tom answered my offers to help with the development of Jekyll by adding me as
a contributor. I&#39;m happy to say that it has come a long way since then, and
I&#39;m very proud to be a part of a team that has pushed this project to new heights.</p>

<p>Thank you to everyone who submitted a pull request, and/or gave me advice along
the way. It has been great fun so far, and I look forward to working with you
all to push out future versions!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Immediate Future of Jekyll]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/18/the-immediate-future-of-jekyll/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T18:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/18/the-immediate-future-of-jekyll</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> is a static blog generator created by <a href="https://github.com/mojombo">Tom Preston-Werner</a>, the
current CEO of <a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a> and one of GitHub&#39;s co-founders, and by <a href="https://github.com/qrush">Nick Quaranto</a>,
who is now at 37signals. Jekyll is <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Sites">pretty freakin&#39; popular</a> and it&#39;s
also the engine that drives <a href="http://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>.</p>

<p>After an hour-long chat with Tom, I&#39;m optimistic about the future of Jekyll. He&#39;s
really excited about where it&#39;s headed and has a vision in mind about what he&#39;d
like it to become.
Here&#39;s what we ironed out during our conversation:</p>

<p>Led by Tom, a Jekyll development team, of which I&#39;m the first recruit, will
be tackling the problems with Jekyll and continuously improving its functionality
and ease-of-use. The focus will remain on making a tool that allows one to easily
create and manage a static blog.</p>

<p>Suuuper basic (unofficial) design principles:</p>

<ol>
<li>Keep it simple</li>
<li>Easy to extend</li>
<li>Solid safe mode (for GitHub Pages)</li>
</ol>

<p>What we need to tackle:</p>

<ol>
<li>Fix bugs (!!)</li>
<li>Decrease build time (!!)</li>
<li>Docs for site</li>
<li>TomDoc everything</li>
<li>Release new site</li>
<li>Finish same site generator</li>
<li>Include some faster LSI</li>
</ol>

<p>Want to help? Check out the <a href="http://git.io/jekyll-discussion">discussion label</a> and add in your two cents.<br>
Want to contribute code? Check out the <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/issues">issues</a> and submit a pull request with
a fix.</p>

<p>I&#39;m really excited about the immediate future of Jekyll and what it will become
in the next 6 months or so and the dev team takes on the issues outlined above.
I hope you&#39;re as excited as we are to get this project back on its feet.</p>

<p>If you want to chat more or have any questions, you know <a href="http://twitter.com/parkr">where to find me</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Letter to Tom Preston-Werner]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T17:03:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;m a huge advocate of static site generators and have always favoured <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> as my go-to static site generator.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, it&#39;s fallen out of active development. I&#39;ve been trying to contact Tom Preston-Werner (<a href="https://github.com/mojombo">@mojombo</a>) about it, but so far: nothing. (To be fair, I have gotten two replies, but they were not productive other than saying that he was looking for new maintainers. That was May 2012.)</p>

<p>So here&#39;s my open letter to you, Tom, about saving   Jekyll from open-source oblivion.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Tom,</p>

<p>Hope you had a pleasant weekend.</p>

<p>Here&#39;s what I wish to see happen with Jekyll:</p>

<ol>
<li>Start an Org on Github and move the Jekyll repo to that org</li>
<li>Add several maintainers to that org (I&#39;d be happy to help out as a maintainer!)</li>
<li>Add another author or two to the Jekyll gem so that we can gem push and release new versions.</li>
<li>Give at least one other person access to push to the source of jekyllrb.com so that the docs can be updated</li>
</ol>

<p>Problem I&#39;m trying to solve:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Jekyll is incredibly popular and is an incredibly powerful tool, but is not being actively maintained centrally, so though the world around it is evolving, it is staying stagnant and plagued by the same issues it has been for the last four years.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Solution:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Add maintainers to Jekyll to help deal with issues, push new versions, and update the documentation when you don&#39;t have the time.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The great thing about version control systems is that changes can always be reverted.</p>

<p>Thanks in advance for your attention to this problem and willingness to help it continue growing.</p>

<p>Warm Regards,<br>
Parker Moore</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
