<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cornell | Hey, I’m Parker.]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/categories/cornell/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-25T15:14:44-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Just Semantics: App.net Alpha]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/09/16/its-just-semantics-app-dot-net-alpha/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-16T19:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/09/16/its-just-semantics-app-dot-net-alpha</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post was originally written as an assignment for <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=90680">INFO 2450: Communication
&amp; Technology</a> taught by Professors <a href="http://infosci.cornell.edu/faculty/jeffrey-hancock">Jeff Hancock</a> and <a href="http://communication.cals.cornell.edu/people/drew-margolin">Drew Margolin</a> in
Fall 2013. The course focuses heavily on design of technologies. The assignment
asked for an evaluation of an online application or product based on the
principles outlined in Donald Norman&#39;s <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Design-Everyday-Things-Donald-Norman/dp/0465067107">&quot;The Design of Everyday Things&quot;</a>. It&#39;s
a very basic look at the technology, but I thought I&#39;d share it anyhow.</p>

<hr>

<p>App.net is a social platform designed from the beginning to be nothing more than
a platform for developers to build great social apps upon. This blog post will
be about the very first application built upon App.net, called Alpha. App.net
will henceforth be referred to as &quot;ADN.&quot;</p>

<p>The main purpose of Alpha is to demonstrate the ADN API in a somewhat familiar
way. Alpha behaves much the way Twitter does: a user creates posts, users can
follow other users and interact with them in the familiar way. The divergence
from Twitter (and other &quot;microblogging&quot; social applications) is twofold: a user
pays for his or her account, and the posts may be longer.</p>

<p>By asking the user to pay for an ADN account (which is used by Alpha as the
poster&#39;s identity), the normal business incentives shift from building an
application (or platform) which optimizes for advertisement revenue to an
application (or platform) which optimizes for the happiness of the user (if
users like to use the service, they will continue to pay the $5/month or
$32/year). Twitter, Facebook, and Google are well-known for accepting user
detriment (in terms of the virtual design of the products) for greater
advertisement revenue. This is not the case with ADN (and by extension, with
Alpha).</p>

<p>On Alpha, posts may be up to 256 characters long and users can choose to attach
media to their posts. The &quot;@&quot; symbol is used to mention another user (the other
user receives a notification when this happens) and the &quot;#&quot; is used to denote
topics. With the longer character limit, one could easily surmise that Alpha is
attempting to make having asynchronous, open conversations online a bit easier.
The openness of being able to write anyone (divergence from Facebook) coupled
with the 256 character limit (a physical constraint) (divergence from Facebook,
and extension of Twitter&#39;s idea that a post should be &quot;bite-sized&quot;) produce a
fantastic application for having chats with anyone about anything in a way
conducive to conciseness and to expressiveness. One common frustration with
Twitter is that conversations on it are very challenging, as 140 characters is
far too few to really say anything substantive. ADN hopes to remedy this
problem, and in my experience, arguments (and general discussions, for that
matter) have been incredibly easy and productive.</p>

<p><img src="/images/app-net/app-net-alpha-feed.png" alt="Screenshot of alpha.app.net"></p>

<p>Above, you see the home screen of Alpha (namely, mine). This shows the user&#39;s
stream. The search box and post box (based on their physical attributes) afford
writing. The change of the &quot;POST&quot; button from grey to a nice deep red-orange
highlights a change of the mapping from a button that may not be pressed to one
that may be pressed (I would consider the change itself feedback). As the user
types in a post, the number (shown here as &quot;256&quot;) decreases by one for each
character that is typed into the box above it, providing very valuable feedback
about the user&#39;s actions. This number&#39;s presence also provides visibility for
the physical constraint placed on the size of the posts allowed in the service.
The buttons on the right of each post afford clicking and change color
(feedback) when clicked. All of the aforementioned design elements, in addition
to the placement of the post box at the top, suggest that the application is
trying to get the user to submit content to his or her stream. The feed below
seems to indicate that the application wishes for perusal and interaction of
other users&#39; posts by the logged-in user.</p>

<p><img src="/images/app-net/app-net-alpha-post.png" alt="Screenshot of a singular post"></p>

<p>As you saw above, each post is given its own box. There are 5 interactions which
only show up when the user mouses-over the post: &quot;Discussion,&quot; &quot;Reply,&quot; &quot;via
(app),&quot; &quot;Mute User,&quot; and &quot;Report&quot;. In order to better facilitate the app&#39;s goal
of interaction, it would make sense for the &quot;Discussion&quot; and &quot;Reply&quot; buttons to
always be shown. This would improve the visibility of the interaction paradigms
and afford interaction without the user making the first move (to mouseover).</p>

<hr>

<p>That&#39;s it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Waleshark, Waleshark, WALEShark]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/12/09/Waleshark-Waleshark-WALEShark/"/>
    <updated>2011-12-09T11:25:32-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/12/09/Waleshark-Waleshark-WALEShark</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is merely to preserve a moment in history. On December 9th, 2011 at 11:25am EST, I received the following email:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>&quot;It is with great pleasure that I send you this invitiation to compete in the 2012 Llangollen International Musical Eisteddfod. Please accept my congratulations. We very much look forward to seeing you in Llangollen. The Music Department will be contacting you separately via e-mail with further details of your competitions.&quot;</p>

<p>Dear CUGC,</p>

<p>We&#39;re in. We made it. In a few short months, we&#39;ll be crossing the pond to compete in the world-renowned Llangollen International Musical Eisteddfod. If we win all our competitions, we will be granted the title of &quot;<strong>Choir of the World.</strong>&quot;</p>

<p>Well, ain&#39;t a that good news!</p>

<p>-- <br>
[ names redacted ] <br>
International Tour Managers <br>
Cornell University Glee Club</p>
</blockquote>

<p>One of the most exciting events thus far in my life. <em>I can&#39;t wait</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On The Future]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/09/25/on-the-future/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-25T13:11:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/09/25/on-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following my arrival at Cornell, I began considering my future much more seriously. What would I like to see myself doing in 5 years? How will I get myself there?</p>

<p>To answer the former question, I see myself working in my career in five years. I will complete my B.S. in Information Science in 2014 and will follow that up with a one-year M.P.S. in the same department. That brings me to May 2015, only four years and a half from how. I expect to find myself applying for full-time positions the previous semester at various tech firms such as Google, Etsy (my hands-down favorite), Hulu and other young firms. I&#39;m working to build up my <a href="http://parkermoore.de/resume/">resumé</a> and fortify my skill set with new languages, algorithms and the like.</p>

<p>Writing this, however, and having been a philosophy/political science/linguistics major last year at McGill, I can&#39;t help by wonder if it&#39;s all worth it. Our society dictates a certain path for future success. Those who are successful have earned a degree from an accredited institution such as Cornell, have perhaps pursued a graduate degree and go off to find a job that pays well. If only we valued our own happiness as much as our salaries, the world might be a better place. I hear talk of hopes to be millionaires and billionaires from students on campus and something about that appalls me but simultaneously excites me. Wouldn&#39;t it be great to have a net worth of over one million dollars?</p>

<p>But we mustn&#39;t forget that some of the happiest people on Earth live on a couple dollars a day. I wish to discover what it is they have that we are so lacking. Quality relationships with our families (the divorce rate is sky-high and I hear stories left and right about parents abandoning their children), perhaps? Or possibly an overwhelming sense of self-worth that our magazines and tabloids deny from us? If we are to have a happier future, collectively, then surely we must figure this out.</p>

<p>Pondering my future is a constant source of worry; not because I don&#39;t think I will be able to find a job, but because I don&#39;t wish to be a slave to my job nor dislike it. Do you know what I mean?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Busy At Cornell]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/08/30/getting-busy-at-cornell/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-30T10:21:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/08/30/getting-busy-at-cornell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve been at <a href="http://www.cornell.edu/">Cornell</a> for a little over a week and I can honestly admit I&#39;ve never been this busy. Thanks to my time at McGill, I have been able to manage my time well, but this is a new level of busy for me!</p>

<p>Coursework has been relatively do-able; I&#39;ve had 3 assignments and 7 readings to do. All in all, not too bad for 3 days of classes. Judging from what I know at this moment, <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=90911"><strong>CS2110</strong></a> is probably going to be the most work. Much of the theory behind the algorithms and mathematical problems is new to me and I suspect that will be the most difficult aspect of this class. <a href="http://www.infosci.cornell.edu/ugrad/CalsMajor.htm"><strong>INFO1300</strong></a> (Intro to Web Design), if I can&#39;t obtain an exemption from the course, will be a cinch. I really don&#39;t expect any issues with that class at all. <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=93470"><strong>INFO 2040</strong></a> will be lots of work, but the concepts we&#39;re learning don&#39;t seem too difficult to grasp. It&#39;s also a huge class, so there&#39;s plenty of opportunity to ask questions to others. It has a good reputation, too. <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=91639"><strong>EDUC2710</strong></a> is already turning out to be one of my favourite classes. Going to be a <em>lot</em> of work, but it&#39;ll be worth it. I was recently given permission to enroll in <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=90949&amp;print"><strong>CS4999</strong></a>, a class where I conduct research and write web apps for college credit. All in all, a good deal.</p>

<p>Cornell offers wonderful academics, but I would argue that the extracurricular opportunities rival those in the academic world. I have chosen to get involved in the music scene here, having been accepted into the <a href="http://www.gleeclub.com/">Cornell Glee Club</a> just last night! A Cappella auditions are this week, and I&#39;m still working on those. I&#39;m also hoping to get involved with the <a href="http://www.cornellsun.com/">Cornell Daily Sun</a> as a web developer. There are a couple other clubs I&#39;m looking into, but those are sort of on hold while auditions ensue.</p>

<p>In addition to all of this, I am a free-lance web developer/designer. I&#39;m really excited to continue my Cornell experience. It&#39;s amazing here and I don&#39;t want to waste even one minute. Let&#39;s end in song:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Far above Cayuga&#39;s waters,<br />
  With its waves of blue,<br />
  Stands our noble Alma Mater,<br />
  Glorious to view.<br />
  <br />
  Lift the chorus, speed it onward,<br />
  Loud her praises tell;<br />
  Hail to thee, our Alma Mater!<br />
  Hail, all hail, Cornell!<br />
  <br />
  Far above the busy humming<br />
  Of the bustling town,<br />
  Reared against the arch of heaven,<br />
  Looks she proudly down.<br />
  <br />
  Lift the chorus, speed it onward,<br />
  Loud her praises tell;<br />
  Hail to thee, our Alma Mater!<br />
  Hail, all hail, Cornell!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I look forward to sharing more with you about Cornell and my experiences here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
