<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: internet | Hey, I’m Parker.]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/categories/internet/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-09T19:14:32-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Without the Internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/11/16/life-without-the-internet/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-16T00:13:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/11/16/life-without-the-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I write this, Cornell&#39;s network is down. It happened at about midnight - all of a sudden, everyone was receiving timeout errors and refused connection errors. I had some more offline work to do, so it didn&#39;t worry me too much, but I found myself anxious. I was anxious about the fact that I couldn&#39;t connect. In mere moments, the full realization that my connection to the world at large (alas, I have a dumb phone) was severed. After a minute or two of contemplation, I felt an overwhelming sense of calm: the world that I am in &mdash; the world of Cornell, and of Ithaca &mdash; was still very much accessible to me. The lack of an internet connection didn&#39;t stop me from going down to the café and enjoying a cappuccino and a nice book, nor did it hinder my ability to see those I care most about here. I felt at peace.</p>

<p>In addition to a newfound realization for what is around me here at Cornell, the internet&#39;s incessant nagging was finally put to rest. No more &quot;1 Unread Message&quot; or &quot;248 Articles to Read&quot;. My lack of connection with the world was, for a moment, a wonderful escape from the unending barrage of information the internet presents on a daily basis.</p>

<p>This got me thinking. Born in the early nineties, I have always known the internet. In fact, I have never known a world without the internet, the personal computer, cell phones, and much more. I am truly a child of the information age. But have I been missing out on something? Constantly battling the perpetual influx of emails, tweets, status updates, and so forth, I wonder if I lose sight of ourselves. Moreover, I wonder if <em>we</em> lose sight of <em>ourselves</em>. (I know I&#39;m not alone when it comes to the relentless flow of information heading my way.) I have a moment, indeed many moments, to truly self-reflect. This, I do believe, is what my generation lacks the most: time for self-reflection.</p>

<p>Thus, I challenge you today, to turn off your internet for an hour, or perhaps two. You may find yourself delighted to see what is awaiting you on the other side.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
