<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: perspective | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/perspective/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-05T22:49:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dealing with Distraction]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/30/dealing-with-distraction/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T15:56:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/30/dealing-with-distraction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dealing with distraction for those of us who live with AD(H)D is a constant struggle, and
can be especially difficult for those of us who must daily solve large, complex problems.
This post describes what it is like to be a programmer with ADD and some strategies I've
developed to help make myself more effective.</p>

<p>To solve complex problems by programmatic means, one needs to be able to focus. To find
the best solution to any problem, one needs to be able to focus. In short, an effective
worker is one who can focus.</p>

<p>For those of us who live with the difficulties of AD(H)D every day, this fact - this
dependence upon a kind of mental discipline - is glaringly obvious. Our constant struggle
to focus means we are not as efficient as our non-ADD peers when asked to complete a
single task. We get distracted by the sound of the wind, the tap of a colleague's fingers
on his desk, or the sound of people talking walking past our window. The slightest noise
or change (by a separate entity) in the visual landscape will cause us to loose our train
of thought nearly immediately.</p>

<p>For those of you who can focus relatively easily in distracting environments, I offer this
metaphor to help you understand a bit more of how it is it live with such an affliction.
Imagine you are swimming in a lake with a basketball. The depth at which you swim is your
level of concentration - the deeper you swim, the more focused you are and thus the less
susceptible to distraction you are. Imagine further that a day's worth of work is like
swimming the length of the lake, and your goal is to swim as deeply as possible for as
far as possible. The problem is that you have to do all this while holding onto the
fully-inflated basketball. The longer you swim underwater, the harder it is to keep the
ball (and yourself) deep underwater. During your swim from one end of the lake to the
other, you are pulled up to the surface very frequently, only able to keep the ball
underground for a short while at a time. This is what it's like to live and work with ADD.</p>

<p>The inability to focus on a given problem for more than a few minutes at a time causes
severe problems for all employees with ADD, but especially for developers who have to
delve into a problem, process it, and produce a solution quickly and efficiently.</p>

<p>The effectiveness of various solutions will vary person to person, but these helped me:</p>

<ul>
<li>Find a quiet, solitary place to work (avoid working in a place where people socialize)</li>
<li>Turn off all notifications when working (fetch updates at will instead)</li>
<li>Play calm, simple music without words, or work in a place where the background noise
doesn't change</li>
<li>Keep the room cool in temperature</li>
<li>Work on one thing at a time and work until it is completed</li>
<li>Plan out finer details for a large project</li>
<li>Get enough sleep</li>
<li>Medicate with some sort of stimulant</li>
<li>Keep your workspace empty of clutter and visual distraction</li>
<li>Keep snacks by your desk (like almonds or dried fruits) to keep your energy up
throughout the day</li>
<li>Exercise to exhaustion at least every other day</li>
<li>Consciously avoid doing several things at once, like listening to a YouTube Lecture and
checking your Twitter feed on your phone at the same time</li>
<li>Avoid depressants like alcohol</li>
<li>Write or engage in a creative, exciting activity which asks for your full concentration</li>
</ul>


<p>Following all of these with ADD can even be a challenge, but limiting the frequency of
distracting stimuli goes a long way to achieving focus and increasing your productivity.</p>

<p>If you have other suggestions, hit me up on <a href="http://alpha.app.net/parkr">ADN</a> or
<a href="http://twitter.com/parkr">Twitter</a>. How do you cope with distractions?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downtime is Good]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/02/11/downtime-is-good/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-11T22:43:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/02/11/downtime-is-good</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just started working as an intern at 6Wunderkinder a couple weeks ago.
I am by no means an expert in devops (hell, I have only dabbled with a little
sysadmin in the past - nothing too serious) and I don't really know what goes
into keeping a huge series of server up and running. I can say, however, that
I know the customer's side of things. I know what it's like to be a user of a
service which periodically goes through downtimes of noticable lengths. (I know
I'm not the only one here so you will probably relate to this observation as
well.</p>

<p>So today there was a blip of downtime for Wunderlist, a really awesome task-
management application by 6Wunderkinder. During this downtime, it occurred to
me: downtime can help the visibility of an application or service.</p>

<p>Hear me out: when the service is running smoothly, few will actually talk about
it. When it goes down, Twitter blows up with complaints and "ZOMG MY LIFE IS
OVER" tweets. These tweets, in a way, promote the service. The more frustrated
the tweet, the more apparent it is that the tweeter cares about this service.</p>

<p>As one who sees these frustrated tweets often about many services, I can only
conclude that a little downtime here and there is a great way for outsiders
to gauge how awesome a service is: if it goes down and people are upset, then
the service is probably worth trying out (once it goes back up again). If the
service goes down and no one cares, then it probably isn't worth your time.</p>

<p>So next time you see angry tweets, write down the name of that service and
check it out once everything is back in order. In all likelihood, you will
like the service, too, and you'll be angrily tweeting next time it goes down.</p>

<p>It's all about perspective.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
