<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: github | Hey, I’m Parker.]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/categories/github/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-17T00:06:23-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Immediate Future of Jekyll]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/18/the-immediate-future-of-jekyll/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T18:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/18/the-immediate-future-of-jekyll</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> is a static blog generator created by <a href="https://github.com/mojombo">Tom Preston-Werner</a>, the
current CEO of <a href="https://github.com">GitHub</a> and one of GitHub&#39;s co-founders, and by <a href="https://github.com/qrush">Nick Quaranto</a>,
who is now at 37signals. Jekyll is <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Sites">pretty freakin&#39; popular</a> and it&#39;s
also the engine that drives <a href="http://pages.github.com/">GitHub Pages</a>.</p>

<p>After an hour-long chat with Tom, I&#39;m optimistic about the future of Jekyll. He&#39;s
really excited about where it&#39;s headed and has a vision in mind about what he&#39;d
like it to become.
Here&#39;s what we ironed out during our conversation:</p>

<p>Led by Tom, a Jekyll development team, of which I&#39;m the first recruit, will
be tackling the problems with Jekyll and continuously improving its functionality
and ease-of-use. The focus will remain on making a tool that allows one to easily
create and manage a static blog.</p>

<p>Suuuper basic (unofficial) design principles:</p>

<ol>
<li>Keep it simple</li>
<li>Easy to extend</li>
<li>Solid safe mode (for GitHub Pages)</li>
</ol>

<p>What we need to tackle:</p>

<ol>
<li>Fix bugs (!!)</li>
<li>Decrease build time (!!)</li>
<li>Docs for site</li>
<li>TomDoc everything</li>
<li>Release new site</li>
<li>Finish same site generator</li>
<li>Include some faster LSI</li>
</ol>

<p>Want to help? Check out the <a href="http://git.io/jekyll-discussion">discussion label</a> and add in your two cents.<br>
Want to contribute code? Check out the <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/issues">issues</a> and submit a pull request with
a fix.</p>

<p>I&#39;m really excited about the immediate future of Jekyll and what it will become
in the next 6 months or so and the dev team takes on the issues outlined above.
I hope you&#39;re as excited as we are to get this project back on its feet.</p>

<p>If you want to chat more or have any questions, you know <a href="http://twitter.com/parkr">where to find me</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Letter to Tom Preston-Werner]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T17:03:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;m a huge advocate of static site generators and have always favoured <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> as my go-to static site generator.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, it&#39;s fallen out of active development. I&#39;ve been trying to contact Tom Preston-Werner (<a href="https://github.com/mojombo">@mojombo</a>) about it, but so far: nothing. (To be fair, I have gotten two replies, but they were not productive other than saying that he was looking for new maintainers. That was May 2012.)</p>

<p>So here&#39;s my open letter to you, Tom, about saving   Jekyll from open-source oblivion.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Tom,</p>

<p>Hope you had a pleasant weekend.</p>

<p>Here&#39;s what I wish to see happen with Jekyll:</p>

<ol>
<li>Start an Org on Github and move the Jekyll repo to that org</li>
<li>Add several maintainers to that org (I&#39;d be happy to help out as a maintainer!)</li>
<li>Add another author or two to the Jekyll gem so that we can gem push and release new versions.</li>
<li>Give at least one other person access to push to the source of jekyllrb.com so that the docs can be updated</li>
</ol>

<p>Problem I&#39;m trying to solve:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Jekyll is incredibly popular and is an incredibly powerful tool, but is not being actively maintained centrally, so though the world around it is evolving, it is staying stagnant and plagued by the same issues it has been for the last four years.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Solution:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Add maintainers to Jekyll to help deal with issues, push new versions, and update the documentation when you don&#39;t have the time.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The great thing about version control systems is that changes can always be reverted.</p>

<p>Thanks in advance for your attention to this problem and willingness to help it continue growing.</p>

<p>Warm Regards,<br>
Parker Moore</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
