<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: education | Hey, I’m Parker.]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/categories/education/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-17T00:59:47-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Grades &amp; the Structure of Higher Education]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/11/01/on-grades-and-the-structure-of-higher-education/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-01T10:17:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/11/01/on-grades-and-the-structure-of-higher-education</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Higher education is messed up. The incentives for learning and the structure of that learning is all wrong.</p>

<p>So what&#39;s this perspective? Well, let&#39;s define elements of this proposition. By &quot;wrong&quot;, I mean &quot;not conducive to the best mastery of the material&quot; and by &quot;structure of that learning&quot;, I&#39;m talking about the overlap of classes &mdash; the simultaneous learning associated with taking more than one class during any one period of time. By &quot;incentives&quot;, I mean &quot;grades&quot;.</p>

<h3>Grades</h3>

<p>Grades suck. Just about every student who&#39;s been evaluated and given a letter to indicate achievement will agree: tears have been shed and jobs have been lost &mdash; careers ruined &mdash; because of a letter.</p>

<p>At grade-obsessed Cornell University, the grade is the entire reason anyone seems to do anything. High grades are rewarded and low grades are punished. But do grades <em>actually</em> measure the success and mastery of the material, or do they just exist to weed out &quot;smart&quot; from &quot;stupid?&quot; I&#39;d argue that grades say nothing about <em>true</em> mastery. Rather, they say &quot;I can take a test well,&quot; or &quot;I can write you an essay you think is good.&quot; But they don&#39;t necessarily say, &quot;I know this and understand every bit of it.&quot; Too often, students memorize but don&#39;t truly understand. Grades exacerbate this problem.</p>

<p>Teachers &mdash; at every level &mdash; should ask more questions which force students to synthesize their knowledge and understanding &mdash; and not bother trying to label the &quot;success&quot; or &quot;failure&quot; with a letter. These letters try to boil a student&#39;s worth down to an arbitrary orthographic symbol. We, the students, should learn by reading and asking questions. The more time we have alone with the material &mdash; for intraspection to develop true understanding &mdash; the more likely it is we will achieve true mastery. Until the teachers believe we have mastered the material, we must continue striving for understanding.</p>

<h3>Structure</h3>

<p>Structure is also a problem. We take up to 6 or 7 courses simultaneously. We ought to focus on just <em>one</em> and work through it until we have achieved true mastery. We must not be distracted by other things. We must immerse ourselves in the topic entirely for an extended period of time.</p>

<p>The simultaneous class system must go. Take a class, perhaps one every three or four weeks, and do not move on until you have mastered the course material. Once one has reached the mastery equivalent to that which the professor believes is true and perfect, then a new topic can be studied. Until then, we mustn&#39;t move on &mdash; mastery is the highest value of education.</p>

<h3>A New System</h3>

<p>This new system will guarantee that every student has the same level of mastery and develops a personal connection with the masters and the material. One topic at a time and commitment to mastery rather than arbitrary grades and skewed test results, this alternate system relies on the intuition of the master. Only the master can know when the student has achieved his or her potential.</p>

<p>Incentives are misaligned. Today&#39;s schooling is no longer about learning &mdash; it&#39;s about being told you&#39;re learning (often when you&#39;re not). It&#39;s time we realign incentives and strive to master the material.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On The Future]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/09/25/on-the-future/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-25T13:11:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/09/25/on-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following my arrival at Cornell, I began considering my future much more seriously. What would I like to see myself doing in 5 years? How will I get myself there?</p>

<p>To answer the former question, I see myself working in my career in five years. I will complete my B.S. in Information Science in 2014 and will follow that up with a one-year M.P.S. in the same department. That brings me to May 2015, only four years and a half from how. I expect to find myself applying for full-time positions the previous semester at various tech firms such as Google, Etsy (my hands-down favorite), Hulu and other young firms. I&#39;m working to build up my <a href="http://parkermoore.de/resume/">resumé</a> and fortify my skill set with new languages, algorithms and the like.</p>

<p>Writing this, however, and having been a philosophy/political science/linguistics major last year at McGill, I can&#39;t help by wonder if it&#39;s all worth it. Our society dictates a certain path for future success. Those who are successful have earned a degree from an accredited institution such as Cornell, have perhaps pursued a graduate degree and go off to find a job that pays well. If only we valued our own happiness as much as our salaries, the world might be a better place. I hear talk of hopes to be millionaires and billionaires from students on campus and something about that appalls me but simultaneously excites me. Wouldn&#39;t it be great to have a net worth of over one million dollars?</p>

<p>But we mustn&#39;t forget that some of the happiest people on Earth live on a couple dollars a day. I wish to discover what it is they have that we are so lacking. Quality relationships with our families (the divorce rate is sky-high and I hear stories left and right about parents abandoning their children), perhaps? Or possibly an overwhelming sense of self-worth that our magazines and tabloids deny from us? If we are to have a happier future, collectively, then surely we must figure this out.</p>

<p>Pondering my future is a constant source of worry; not because I don&#39;t think I will be able to find a job, but because I don&#39;t wish to be a slave to my job nor dislike it. Do you know what I mean?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Busy At Cornell]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/08/30/getting-busy-at-cornell/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-30T10:21:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/08/30/getting-busy-at-cornell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve been at <a href="http://www.cornell.edu/">Cornell</a> for a little over a week and I can honestly admit I&#39;ve never been this busy. Thanks to my time at McGill, I have been able to manage my time well, but this is a new level of busy for me!</p>

<p>Coursework has been relatively do-able; I&#39;ve had 3 assignments and 7 readings to do. All in all, not too bad for 3 days of classes. Judging from what I know at this moment, <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=90911"><strong>CS2110</strong></a> is probably going to be the most work. Much of the theory behind the algorithms and mathematical problems is new to me and I suspect that will be the most difficult aspect of this class. <a href="http://www.infosci.cornell.edu/ugrad/CalsMajor.htm"><strong>INFO1300</strong></a> (Intro to Web Design), if I can&#39;t obtain an exemption from the course, will be a cinch. I really don&#39;t expect any issues with that class at all. <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=93470"><strong>INFO 2040</strong></a> will be lots of work, but the concepts we&#39;re learning don&#39;t seem too difficult to grasp. It&#39;s also a huge class, so there&#39;s plenty of opportunity to ask questions to others. It has a good reputation, too. <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=91639"><strong>EDUC2710</strong></a> is already turning out to be one of my favourite classes. Going to be a <em>lot</em> of work, but it&#39;ll be worth it. I was recently given permission to enroll in <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=90949&amp;print"><strong>CS4999</strong></a>, a class where I conduct research and write web apps for college credit. All in all, a good deal.</p>

<p>Cornell offers wonderful academics, but I would argue that the extracurricular opportunities rival those in the academic world. I have chosen to get involved in the music scene here, having been accepted into the <a href="http://www.gleeclub.com/">Cornell Glee Club</a> just last night! A Cappella auditions are this week, and I&#39;m still working on those. I&#39;m also hoping to get involved with the <a href="http://www.cornellsun.com/">Cornell Daily Sun</a> as a web developer. There are a couple other clubs I&#39;m looking into, but those are sort of on hold while auditions ensue.</p>

<p>In addition to all of this, I am a free-lance web developer/designer. I&#39;m really excited to continue my Cornell experience. It&#39;s amazing here and I don&#39;t want to waste even one minute. Let&#39;s end in song:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Far above Cayuga&#39;s waters,<br />
  With its waves of blue,<br />
  Stands our noble Alma Mater,<br />
  Glorious to view.<br />
  <br />
  Lift the chorus, speed it onward,<br />
  Loud her praises tell;<br />
  Hail to thee, our Alma Mater!<br />
  Hail, all hail, Cornell!<br />
  <br />
  Far above the busy humming<br />
  Of the bustling town,<br />
  Reared against the arch of heaven,<br />
  Looks she proudly down.<br />
  <br />
  Lift the chorus, speed it onward,<br />
  Loud her praises tell;<br />
  Hail to thee, our Alma Mater!<br />
  Hail, all hail, Cornell!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I look forward to sharing more with you about Cornell and my experiences here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Git Cheat-Sheet]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/05/30/git/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/05/30/git</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was recently cleaning out my room at home (I&#39;m back from college for the summer) and found an old <code>git</code> cheat-sheet. I thought I would electronically log it for future reference (as though I don&#39;t use git every day or something...).</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash">git init
git clone git://github.com/username/repo.git
git add filename
git status <span class="o">[</span>-s]
git diff <span class="o">[</span>--cached] <span class="o">[</span>HEAD] <span class="o">[</span>--stat]
git commit <span class="o">[</span>-a] <span class="o">[</span>-m <span class="s2">"commit message"</span><span class="o">]</span>
git reset <span class="o">[</span>HEAD]
git rm <span class="o">[</span>--cached] filename
    <span class="c"># (by adding --cached, the file that's deleted</span>
    <span class="c"># will be left in your local directory)</span>

git branch branchname
git checkout branchname
git checkout -b branchname
git branch -d branchname <span class="c"># (delete)</span>

git merge branchname <span class="c"># (merges 'branchname' to current branch)</span>
git mv file newfile
git log <span class="o">[</span>--oneline] <span class="o">[</span>--graph] <span class="o">[</span>branchname] <span class="o">[</span>^compared_branch_name]
git tag -a msg commit_shortcode

git remote <span class="o">[</span>-v]
git remote add <span class="nb">alias </span>git@github.com:username/repo.git
git fetch <span class="nb">alias</span>
</code></pre></div>]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
