<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: release | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/release/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-04T10:57:45-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jekyll 1.0 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T00:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I'm proud to announce the release of Jekyll 1.0. There are a million
goodies and fixes to enjoy, and we're (the still-active Jekyll core team
members: Tom, Matt and I) really excited to share this first major release
with you. Be sure to follow <a href="http://twitter.com/jekyllrb">@jekyllrb</a> for
updates on future releases and links to cool plugins.</p>

<p>Some quick highlights:</p>

<ul>
<li>New subcommands: new, build, serve, and import</li>
<li>Amazing new docs at http://jekyllrb.com (thanks to @cobyism)</li>
<li><code>jekyll new</code> creates a new scaffold so you can get blogging even faster</li>
<li>Drafts, i.e. posts without dates</li>
<li>New "excerpt" feature on posts</li>
<li>Timezone configuration</li>
<li>'gist' liquid tag</li>
<li>Source directory protection</li>
</ul>


<p>... and <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/v1.0.0/History.txt">so much more</a>!</p>

<p>We also have an <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/upgrading/">Upgrading</a> page that clarifies
some breaking changes and tips for upgrading to Jekyll 1.0.</p>

<p>As many of you know, Jekyll lay mostly stagnant for quite some time. At 0.11.2 and
0.12.0, it was pretty stable. It had some annoying bugs, but nothing much that
couldn't be worked around or monkey-patched.</p>

<p>After using Jekyll last summer to help build
<a href="http://cals.cornell.edu">Cornell's College of Agriculture and Life Sciences website</a>,
I took a renewed interest in seeing this project move forward. Last December,
Tom answered my offers to help with the development of Jekyll by adding me as
a contributor. I'm happy to say that it has come a long way since then, and
I'm very proud to be a part of a team that has pushed this project to new heights.</p>

<p>Thank you to everyone who submitted a pull request, and/or gave me advice along
the way. It has been great fun so far, and I look forward to working with you
all to push out future versions!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
