<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: repost | Hey, I’m Parker.]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/categories/repost/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-09T19:14:32-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Mustn't Idle]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/22/we-mustnt-idle/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T02:12:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/22/we-mustnt-idle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our legacies on this Beautiful Earth are inextricably tied to the work we do, the
principles we stand for and the messages we spread. The apathetic nature of many of my
peers nowadays is heresy to the nth degree, and we can no longer stand idly by and watch
young people refusing to talk about the hard issues. If we’re to make any progress and
maintain this More Perfect Union, we had better get our act together and stand and fight
for the things we believe in.</p>

<p>It comes with a price, however. We must be informed. We must read the arguments of the
other side, debate them and reformulate our stance given the new evidence. In the same
way Newton used this inductive methods to formulate his three famous Natural Laws, we
must start with a problem we observe in our society, generalize a solution in the form
of legislation, judicial action or grassroots campaigning, and revise our message as new
information becomes available.</p>

<p>It is not enough to let Gov majors, English majors and law students run the country,
making sweeping decisions about how we may live our lives. It is not enough to defer to
those with means and wealth – those with the ability to run a traditional campaign for
public office and influence those in public office – in fact, it is the worst offense to
this Great Nation to allow the aristocracy of special interets to continue determining
the rule of law. We must stand up, as citizens, and fight for what sparks fire in our
bellies! We must stand up, as citizens, and say “enough is enough” to special interests
and lobbyists who control Washington. Now is our time. If our country is to change for
the better, it will be because we – the citizens – made our voices heard and fought with
much gnashing of teeth for what we believe in and what we know is right.</p>

<p>This is the imperative of our generation. Let us act!</p>

<p>This post was originally published on <a href="https://medium.com/i-m-h-o/d5bf40927b1a">Medium</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
