<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: cornell | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/cornell/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-05T17:32:33-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's Just Semantics: App.net Alpha]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/09/16/its-just-semantics-app-dot-net-alpha/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-16T19:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/09/16/its-just-semantics-app-dot-net-alpha</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post was <a href="http://2450fall2013.ning.com/groups/red-2450/blog/it-s-just-semantics-app-net-alpha">originally written</a> as an assignment for <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=90680">INFO 2450: Communication
&amp; Technology</a> taught by Professors <a href="http://infosci.cornell.edu/faculty/jeffrey-hancock">Jeff Hancock</a> and <a href="http://communication.cals.cornell.edu/people/drew-margolin">Drew Margolin</a> in
Fall 2013. The course focuses heavily on design of technologies. The assignment
asked for an evaluation of an online application or product based on the
principles outlined in Donald Norman's <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Design-Everyday-Things-Donald-Norman/dp/0465067107">"The Design of Everyday Things"</a>. It's
a very basic look at the technology, but I thought I'd share it anyhow.</p>

<hr />

<p>App.net is a social platform designed from the beginning to be nothing more than
a platform for developers to build great social apps upon. This blog post will
be about the very first application built upon App.net, called Alpha. App.net
will henceforth be referred to as "ADN."</p>

<p>The main purpose of Alpha is to demonstrate the ADN API in a somewhat familiar
way. Alpha behaves much the way Twitter does: a user creates posts, users can
follow other users and interact with them in the familiar way. The divergence
from Twitter (and other "microblogging" social applications) is twofold: a user
pays for his or her account, and the posts may be longer.</p>

<p>By asking the user to pay for an ADN account (which is used by Alpha as the
poster's identity), the normal business incentives shift from building an
application (or platform) which optimizes for advertisement revenue to an
application (or platform) which optimizes for the happiness of the user (if
users like to use the service, they will continue to pay the $5/month or
$32/year). Twitter, Facebook, and Google are well-known for accepting user
detriment (in terms of the virtual design of the products) for greater
advertisement revenue. This is not the case with ADN (and by extension, with
Alpha).</p>

<p>On Alpha, posts may be up to 256 characters long and users can choose to attach
media to their posts. The "@" symbol is used to mention another user (the other
user receives a notification when this happens) and the "#" is used to denote
topics. With the longer character limit, one could easily surmise that Alpha is
attempting to make having asynchronous, open conversations online a bit easier.
The openness of being able to write anyone (divergence from Facebook) coupled
with the 256 character limit (a physical constraint) (divergence from Facebook,
and extension of Twitter's idea that a post should be "bite-sized") produce a
fantastic application for having chats with anyone about anything in a way
conducive to conciseness and to expressiveness. One common frustration with
Twitter is that conversations on it are very challenging, as 140 characters is
far too few to really say anything substantive. ADN hopes to remedy this
problem, and in my experience, arguments (and general discussions, for that
matter) have been incredibly easy and productive.</p>

<p><img src="/images/app-net/app-net-alpha-feed.png" alt="Screenshot of alpha.app.net" /></p>

<p>Above, you see the home screen of Alpha (namely, mine). This shows the user's
stream. The search box and post box (based on their physical attributes) afford
writing. The change of the "POST" button from grey to a nice deep red-orange
highlights a change of the mapping from a button that may not be pressed to one
that may be pressed (I would consider the change itself feedback). As the user
types in a post, the number (shown here as "256") decreases by one for each
character that is typed into the box above it, providing very valuable feedback
about the user's actions. This number's presence also provides visibility for
the physical constraint placed on the size of the posts allowed in the service.
The buttons on the right of each post afford clicking and change color
(feedback) when clicked. All of the aforementioned design elements, in addition
to the placement of the post box at the top, suggest that the application is
trying to get the user to submit content to his or her stream. The feed below
seems to indicate that the application wishes for perusal and interaction of
other users' posts by the logged-in user.</p>

<p><img src="/images/app-net/app-net-alpha-post.png" alt="Screenshot of a singular post" /></p>

<p>As you saw above, each post is given its own box. There are 5 interactions which
only show up when the user mouses-over the post: "Discussion," "Reply," "via
(app)," "Mute User," and "Report". In order to better facilitate the app's goal
of interaction, it would make sense for the "Discussion" and "Reply" buttons to
always be shown. This would improve the visibility of the interaction paradigms
and afford interaction without the user making the first move (to mouseover).</p>

<hr />

<p>That's it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
