<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tech | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-06T10:29:30-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Installing Command-T with OS X Maverick's Built-In Vim]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2014/01/02/installing-command-t-with-os-x-mavericks-built-in-vim/"/>
    <updated>2014-01-02T01:03:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2014/01/02/installing-command-t-with-os-x-mavericks-built-in-vim</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was fortunate enough to, just today, pick up a new computer. My first hardware
in over 4 years, I had been holding off. Once my trusty MacBook Pro bit the dust
last night and I found out the repair cost was extraordinary, I bit the bullet.</p>

<p>So, you're probably in a similar place. You relatively recently got a shiny new
Macintosh and you're so excited to start writing code and making a difference
with those skillz of yours. Except one this is missing: <a href="https://github.com/wincent/Command-T">Command-T</a>.</p>

<p>Lucky for you, sir, I am here to help. OS X Maverick's built-in vim distribution
comes with Ruby support already (which it needs for Command-T) so you're good
there. Now you need to download and compile Command-T. Should be easy, right?
Well, not quite.</p>

<p>Mavericks was notable for Ruby users because it ships with Ruby 2.0. All
previous versions that I had ever used shipped with 1.8.7 so this was a huge
bonus. Problem is, your pre-installed vim wasn't compiled with 2.0.0, it was
compiled with 1.8.7.</p>

<p>To check this, run the following in vim in NORMAL mode:</p>

<pre><code class="text">:ruby puts "#{RUBY_VERSION}-p#{RUBY_PATCHLEVEL}"
</code></pre>

<p>For me, that output <code>1.8.7-p358</code>. So that means the Ruby verison that vim is
using is <code>1.8.7-p358</code>, and we need to compile Command-T with that version. To do
so, install it:</p>

<pre><code class="bash">$ rbenv install 1.8.7-p358
</code></pre>

<p>Boom! Now download and install Command-T:</p>

<pre><code class="bash">$ git clone https://github.com/wincent/Command-T.git ~/.vim/bundle/Command-T
$ cd ~/.vim/bundle/Command-T # for tpope's Pathogen
$ rbenv local 1.8.7-p358
$ rbenv rehash
$ gem install bundler
$ bundle install
$ bundle exec rake make
</code></pre>

<p>Aaaaand boom, you're done. Open up <code>vim</code> and type your leaderkey then <code>t</code> (for
me, that's <code>,t</code>) to launch the prompt.</p>

<p>If you get a weird SIGTERM error when you launch <code>vim</code>, then you installed
Command-T with the wrong Ruby version. Remove <code>ruby/command-t/ext.bundle</code> and
try again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fixing Memory Issues in Dokku hosted on DigitalOcean 512MB Droplet]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/12/21/fixing-memory-issues-in-dokku-hosted-on-digitalocean-512mb-droplet/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-21T12:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/12/21/fixing-memory-issues-in-dokku-hosted-on-digitalocean-512mb-droplet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As many other Heroku customers, I rejoiced when <a href="https://github.com/progrium/dokku">Dokku</a> was released. To have
complete freedom to host as many apps with whatever databases or other plugins
I wanted -- all for the cost of a small VM -- was wonderful news.</p>

<p>I decided, for cost's sake, to boot up one of those famed $5 <a href="https://digitalocean.com">DigitalOcean</a>
Droplets. I didn't see that DigitalOcean provides an "app" for Dokku, so I
created a vanilla box of Ubuntu 13.04 and pressed on. I got everything up and
running and went to go deploy my first app, only to see this when I ran
<code>git push</code>:</p>

<pre><code class="text">runtime: panic before malloc heap initialized
fatal error: runtime: cannot allocate heap metadata
</code></pre>

<p>Well, golly, that sure is unhelpful. Looks like 512MB doesn't cut it. Luckily,
we can avoid paying the extra $5/mo for the 1GB version by running the following
as <code>root</code>:</p>

<pre><code class="bash">dd if=/dev/zero of=/extraswap bs=1M count=512
mkswap /extraswap
</code></pre>

<p>Then adding the following to your <code>/etc/fstab</code> file so the swap persists between
reboots:</p>

<pre><code class="text">/extraswap         none            swap    sw                0       0
</code></pre>

<p>Then run this to enable <code>/extraswap</code> for swapping:</p>

<pre><code class="bash">swapon -a
</code></pre>

<p>Boom. Now re-run <code>git push</code> and you're in business. Magic!</p>

<p>Credit goes to the brilliant <a href="https://github.com/dhassler">@dhassler</a> for <a href="https://github.com/dotcloud/docker/issues/1555#issuecomment-22874190">the idea and the code</a>. Just
thought I'd share and preserve for my own benefit in the future.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking Over Someone Else's Open-Source Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/11/04/taking-over-someone-elses-open-source-project/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-04T21:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/11/04/taking-over-someone-elses-open-source-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last December (2012), <a href="http://tom.preston-werner.com">Tom Preston-Werner</a> granted me <a href="/images/mojombo-added-parkr-to-jekyll.png">push &amp; pull access to
mojombo/jekyll</a>. I had written a <a href="/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner/">letter to Tom about the future of Jekyll</a>
and after a bit of persistence on my part, he relented:</p>

<p><img src="/images/mojombo-added-parkr-to-jekyll.png" alt="mojombo added parkr to mojombo/jekyll" /></p>

<p>After a somewhat lengthy (and <a href="/images/jekyll-shall-inherit-the-earth.png">amusing</a>) conversation via Skype, I knew what
Tom's priorities were for the project and where I could help. I started off
trimming down the number of open issues. At the time, they numbered just over 300.
After a quick visit to Buffalo to tackle some issues with <a href="http://quaran.to">Nick Quaranto</a> at a
Buffalo <a href="http://openhack.github.io">OpenHack</a> meetup at <a href="http://coworkbuffalo.com">CoworkBuffalo</a>, we were down to fewer than 200
open issues. I continued to work through them (much to my parents' dismay) all
through Winter Break. I was making good progress in the triage process: I knew
what many of the problems were with v0.12.1 and was formulating ideas about how
we might go about fixing them.</p>

<p><img src="/images/jekyll-shall-inherit-the-earth.png" alt="jekyll shall inherit the earth" /></p>

<p>In January, I flew out to San Francisco to visit my sister for a week. I setup a
meeting with Tom to talk more about Jekyll and a plan for moving forward to a
v1.0.0 release. After about an hour or so at GitHub's office in SoMa, talking
through various PR's, Tom said I could start merging pull requests.</p>

<p>Consultation with Tom was challenging (he runs a multi-million dollar company
after all), as it was increasingly difficult for him to find time for Jekyll.
Despite <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/issues/578#issuecomment-11414645">announcing that he was going to commit some of his "20% time" to Jekyll</a>,
he eventually abandoned that as impractical. As time went on, I received fewer
replies to my emails and eventually stopped sending anything that didn't
absolutely <em>require</em> Tom's input.</p>

<p>In March, I knew I needed more help. Tom wasn't able to give much time and I
was trying to tackle this project alone. I had noticed that <a href="http://mattr.info">Matt Rogers</a>
shared my vision for Jekyll, so I asked Tom to add him on as a contributor to
the repo. By v1.0.3, he had started merging pull requests like a BAW$ and was
the sanity to my ridiculously-obsessed, inexperienced mind. Since Matt joined, I
haven't really heard much from Tom. I write the occasional email and get the
occasional reply but he's essentially phased out of the normal development of
Jekyll. Matt &amp; I have essentially taken over the project altogether.</p>

<p>By May, we were ready to ship v1.0.0. With the help of all the amazing
contributors, Matt, and my many mentors along the way, I finally ran
<code>rake release</code> for 1.0. The project was ours.</p>

<p>Since realizing that this product has few constraints outside of those I've
constructed for it in my mind (no one is going to tell me, "No, you may not
implement that feature or add that enhancement" without a valid argument as to
my solution's invalidity), I've been thinking about what it means to take over
someone else's project. <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/commit/d189e05d236769c1e5594af9db4d6eacb86fc16e">Jekyll is 5 years old.</a> I wasn't there in 2008 when
it was first born as <code>autoblog</code>. Jekyll has changed a lot, as has its vision and
purpose. It's used by lots of people now, whether via <a href="http://pages.github.com">GitHub Pages</a> or
locally.</p>

<p>Taking over someone else's project takes a deep understanding of what the
project is and what it should be. As much as I wish Jekyll could make me
kräuterquark, that's outside the scope of the project. Developing that lens is
crucial when taking over someone else's project.</p>

<p>Mentoring on the part of the original owner/previous maintainer(s) is
exceedingly significant in the development of this critical lens. I am so
grateful that I was able to meet up with Tom back in January and to have some
amount of input from him as I understood what the project should be.</p>

<p>It would be ill-advised to take over someone else's project without a partner.
Once Matt joined the team, Tom was able to step back into a much lesser role.
If I had tried to do what I did without any guidance (or at least sanity
checks), Jekyll v1.0.0 would have been a complete shit-show.</p>

<p>Trust in the community must also be earned. If people highly doubted my ability
to handle Jekyll, Tom would have likely removed me and found a replacement. I
argued a lot and got into some pretty heated debates at the beginning. There
were a couple people who didn't share the vision that I had inherited from Tom
and stopped contributing to the project altogether. I feel like we now have a
pretty great community around Jekyll and are able to help each other out and
share cool plugins and sites that we made for/with Jekyll.</p>

<p>Taking over someone else's open-source project was new terrain for me in
December, and still is today. It can be successful with the right amount of
mentoring and gradual removal of trusted feedback by the previous maintainer(s).</p>

<p>With some old projects that are brought back to life by the passing of the
torch, the new maintainers are able to experience the added bonus of feeling
like Frankenstein, which, I will say, is a pretty cool feeling.</p>

<p><img src="/images/it-lives.jpg" alt="igor" /></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dealing with Distraction]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/30/dealing-with-distraction/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-30T15:56:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/30/dealing-with-distraction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Dealing with distraction for those of us who live with AD(H)D is a constant struggle, and
can be especially difficult for those of us who must daily solve large, complex problems.
This post describes what it is like to be a programmer with ADD and some strategies I've
developed to help make myself more effective.</p>

<p>To solve complex problems by programmatic means, one needs to be able to focus. To find
the best solution to any problem, one needs to be able to focus. In short, an effective
worker is one who can focus.</p>

<p>For those of us who live with the difficulties of AD(H)D every day, this fact - this
dependence upon a kind of mental discipline - is glaringly obvious. Our constant struggle
to focus means we are not as efficient as our non-ADD peers when asked to complete a
single task. We get distracted by the sound of the wind, the tap of a colleague's fingers
on his desk, or the sound of people talking walking past our window. The slightest noise
or change (by a separate entity) in the visual landscape will cause us to loose our train
of thought nearly immediately.</p>

<p>For those of you who can focus relatively easily in distracting environments, I offer this
metaphor to help you understand a bit more of how it is it live with such an affliction.
Imagine you are swimming in a lake with a basketball. The depth at which you swim is your
level of concentration - the deeper you swim, the more focused you are and thus the less
susceptible to distraction you are. Imagine further that a day's worth of work is like
swimming the length of the lake, and your goal is to swim as deeply as possible for as
far as possible. The problem is that you have to do all this while holding onto the
fully-inflated basketball. The longer you swim underwater, the harder it is to keep the
ball (and yourself) deep underwater. During your swim from one end of the lake to the
other, you are pulled up to the surface very frequently, only able to keep the ball
underground for a short while at a time. This is what it's like to live and work with ADD.</p>

<p>The inability to focus on a given problem for more than a few minutes at a time causes
severe problems for all employees with ADD, but especially for developers who have to
delve into a problem, process it, and produce a solution quickly and efficiently.</p>

<p>The effectiveness of various solutions will vary person to person, but these helped me:</p>

<ul>
<li>Find a quiet, solitary place to work (avoid working in a place where people socialize)</li>
<li>Turn off all notifications when working (fetch updates at will instead)</li>
<li>Play calm, simple music without words, or work in a place where the background noise
doesn't change</li>
<li>Keep the room cool in temperature</li>
<li>Work on one thing at a time and work until it is completed</li>
<li>Plan out finer details for a large project</li>
<li>Get enough sleep</li>
<li>Medicate with some sort of stimulant</li>
<li>Keep your workspace empty of clutter and visual distraction</li>
<li>Keep snacks by your desk (like almonds or dried fruits) to keep your energy up
throughout the day</li>
<li>Exercise to exhaustion at least every other day</li>
<li>Consciously avoid doing several things at once, like listening to a YouTube Lecture and
checking your Twitter feed on your phone at the same time</li>
<li>Avoid depressants like alcohol</li>
<li>Write or engage in a creative, exciting activity which asks for your full concentration</li>
</ul>


<p>Following all of these with ADD can even be a challenge, but limiting the frequency of
distracting stimuli goes a long way to achieving focus and increasing your productivity.</p>

<p>If you have other suggestions, hit me up on <a href="http://alpha.app.net/parkr">ADN</a> or
<a href="http://twitter.com/parkr">Twitter</a>. How do you cope with distractions?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jekyll 1.0 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T00:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I'm proud to announce the release of Jekyll 1.0. There are a million
goodies and fixes to enjoy, and we're (the still-active Jekyll core team
members: Tom, Matt and I) really excited to share this first major release
with you. Be sure to follow <a href="http://twitter.com/jekyllrb">@jekyllrb</a> for
updates on future releases and links to cool plugins.</p>

<p>Some quick highlights:</p>

<ul>
<li>New subcommands: new, build, serve, and import</li>
<li>Amazing new docs at http://jekyllrb.com (thanks to @cobyism)</li>
<li><code>jekyll new</code> creates a new scaffold so you can get blogging even faster</li>
<li>Drafts, i.e. posts without dates</li>
<li>New "excerpt" feature on posts</li>
<li>Timezone configuration</li>
<li>'gist' liquid tag</li>
<li>Source directory protection</li>
</ul>


<p>... and <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/v1.0.0/History.txt">so much more</a>!</p>

<p>We also have an <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/upgrading/">Upgrading</a> page that clarifies
some breaking changes and tips for upgrading to Jekyll 1.0.</p>

<p>As many of you know, Jekyll lay mostly stagnant for quite some time. At 0.11.2 and
0.12.0, it was pretty stable. It had some annoying bugs, but nothing much that
couldn't be worked around or monkey-patched.</p>

<p>After using Jekyll last summer to help build
<a href="http://cals.cornell.edu">Cornell's College of Agriculture and Life Sciences website</a>,
I took a renewed interest in seeing this project move forward. Last December,
Tom answered my offers to help with the development of Jekyll by adding me as
a contributor. I'm happy to say that it has come a long way since then, and
I'm very proud to be a part of a team that has pushed this project to new heights.</p>

<p>Thank you to everyone who submitted a pull request, and/or gave me advice along
the way. It has been great fun so far, and I look forward to working with you
all to push out future versions!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
