<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: tech | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/tech/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2013-05-06T10:56:31+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jekyll 1.0 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T00:59:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I'm proud to announce the release of Jekyll 1.0. There are a million
goodies and fixes to enjoy, and we're (the still-active Jekyll core team
members: Tom, Matt and I) really excited to share this first major release
with you. Be sure to follow <a href="http://twitter.com/jekyllrb">@jekyllrb</a> for
updates on future releases and links to cool plugins.</p>

<p>Some quick highlights:</p>

<ul>
<li>New subcommands: new, build, serve, and import</li>
<li>Amazing new docs at http://jekyllrb.com (thanks to @cobyism)</li>
<li><code>jekyll new</code> creates a new scaffold so you can get blogging even faster</li>
<li>Drafts, i.e. posts without dates</li>
<li>New "excerpt" feature on posts</li>
<li>Timezone configuration</li>
<li>'gist' liquid tag</li>
<li>Source directory protection</li>
</ul>


<p>... and <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/v1.0.0/History.txt">so much more</a>!</p>

<p>We also have an <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/upgrading/">Upgrading</a> page that clarifies
some breaking changes and tips for upgrading to Jekyll 1.0.</p>

<p>As many of you know, Jekyll lay mostly stagnant for quite some time. At 0.11.2 and
0.12.0, it was pretty stable. It had some annoying bugs, but nothing much that
couldn't be worked around or monkey-patched.</p>

<p>After using Jekyll last summer to help build
<a href="http://cals.cornell.edu">Cornell's College of Agriculture and Life Sciences website</a>,
I took a renewed interest in seeing this project move forward. Last December,
Tom answered my offers to help with the development of Jekyll by adding me as
a contributor. I'm happy to say that it has come a long way since then, and
I'm very proud to be a part of a team that has pushed this project to new heights.</p>

<p>Thank you to everyone who submitted a pull request, and/or gave me advice along
the way. It has been great fun so far, and I look forward to working with you
all to push out future versions!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downtime is Good]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/02/11/downtime-is-good/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-11T22:43:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/02/11/downtime-is-good</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just started working as an intern at 6Wunderkinder a couple weeks ago.
I am by no means an expert in devops (hell, I have only dabbled with a little
sysadmin in the past - nothing too serious) and I don't really know what goes
into keeping a huge series of server up and running. I can say, however, that
I know the customer's side of things. I know what it's like to be a user of a
service which periodically goes through downtimes of noticable lengths. (I know
I'm not the only one here so you will probably relate to this observation as
well.</p>

<p>So today there was a blip of downtime for Wunderlist, a really awesome task-
management application by 6Wunderkinder. During this downtime, it occurred to
me: downtime can help the visibility of an application or service.</p>

<p>Hear me out: when the service is running smoothly, few will actually talk about
it. When it goes down, Twitter blows up with complaints and "ZOMG MY LIFE IS
OVER" tweets. These tweets, in a way, promote the service. The more frustrated
the tweet, the more apparent it is that the tweeter cares about this service.</p>

<p>As one who sees these frustrated tweets often about many services, I can only
conclude that a little downtime here and there is a great way for outsiders
to gauge how awesome a service is: if it goes down and people are upset, then
the service is probably worth trying out (once it goes back up again). If the
service goes down and no one cares, then it probably isn't worth your time.</p>

<p>So next time you see angry tweets, write down the name of that service and
check it out once everything is back in order. In all likelihood, you will
like the service, too, and you'll be angrily tweeting next time it goes down.</p>

<p>It's all about perspective.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Favourite Apps in 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/01/03/my-favourite-apps-in-2012/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-03T01:36:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/01/03/my-favourite-apps-in-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below is a list of the apps I wouldn't have wanted to live without this year.
To be fair to everyone, I've listed them in alphabetical order.</p>

<p>I know some apps are missing links to various versions, but if I didn't use it,
then I felt it was best not to include a link to it on this list.</p>

<h3>101 Airborne (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/101-airborne/id531317549?mt=8">iPhone</a>)</h3>

<p>At this moment, this is one of only two games which I have installed on my iPhone.
I have thoroughly enjoyed playing this game, and it is incredibly well-done,
to boot.</p>

<h3>Diet Coda (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/diet-coda/id500906297?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>When I had to have the logic board in my MacBook Pro replaced, I had to hand in
my computer for a week. I am practically addicted to development, and this app
by Panic, Inc. of Portland, Oregon, served me well during those tough times.</p>

<h3>Dropbox (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dropbox/id327630330?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/install">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Dropbox gives me the freedom to aimlessly roam between devices without losing
any progress. I can work on my mac for a bit, then pick up my iPad and resume
my work right then and there. Dropbox far surpasses the ease-of-use of competitors
such as Box.com, and its native Mac application is far less intrusive, as well.</p>

<h3>Google+ (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google+/id447119634?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>I'm a social media weirdo. I have to try out every one that comes along. I even
tried out <a href="http://app.net">app.net</a> for a while (I still have an account there).
I started using this app far more after the amazing redesign which happened
right around Christmastime. It was indeed an enjoyable occasion. I use G+ to stay
in contact with friends who now work at Google and with friends of mine who insist
on Google-only living: an Android phone, Google+ to communicate (Messenger), and
Google Docs to collaborate.</p>

<h3>Google Chrome (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/chrome/id535886823?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en/chrome/browser/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Chrome on Mac is absolutely awesome. I use it obsessively.</p>

<p>Chrome on the iPhone is something I had to warm up to a bit more. It behaves far
differently than Safari on iOS and the controls are in completely different places.
After some adjustment, I've come to appreciate its incredible flexibility and
strength in the mobile realm.</p>

<h3>Google Maps (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google-maps/id585027354?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>Apple Maps has yet to lead me to a hospital that isn't there, or on a road that has
been demolished, but I still missed the Google Maps speed and accuracy. I have also
found that Google Maps is far better for finding nearby amenities, such as coffee,
gas, and food.</p>

<h3>Google Translate (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google-translate/id414706506?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>While I am relatively proficient in the language, learning German is a process.
I have found this app very helpful during my studies and even when having a
causal conversation over Skype in German.</p>

<h3>Gmail (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/gmail-email-from-google/id422689480?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>As with G+ above, the redesign really did it for me. It was, all of a sudden,
a reliable, beautiful, and agile experience, to use this app. It was incredibly
buggy before (it seemed to be a product from Google's insistence that online
mobile apps will be dominant, over native apps), but it has come a long way.</p>

<h3>iA Writer (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ia-writer/id392502056?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ia-writer/id439623248?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Whenever I have a thought that I want to remember and ponder later, I write it
down in a note. This usually happens while I am on-the-go. I will then come
back later and review my thoughts and ideas in iA Writer for Mac. I am so thankful
that iA Writer offers syncing through services like iCloud and Dropbox.</p>

<p>I have even been known to write essays on my iPhone of 1000+ words while I walk
between classes, to dinner in Collegetown, and to and from rehearsals. Two of the
three "A" papers I wrote last year (one writes few papers when studying engineering)
were written almost entirely in iA Writer for iOS.</p>

<h3>Instapaper (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/instapaper/id288545208?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>After much consideration, I decided to include this app on my list. I have used
Instapaper for many years now, and have truly enjoyed using it. It has,
unforunately, become a repository for articles I'd like to read, but probably
never will. I found Instapaper very useful, however, to pass the time during
long plane/car/bus rides, as well as long layovers between flights.</p>

<h3>iTerm2 (<a href="http://www.iterm2.com/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Almost all of my development before May this year was done in Terminal.app.
While I have appreciated its service, I decided to move on to iTerm2 upon a
recommendation from a friend. iTerm2 is light and doesn't have any weird "Mac
baggage" which Terminal.app does. It's simple to configure (though there are
far too many configuration options, in my opinion), and easy to use.</p>

<h3>Lightroom 4 (<a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/photoshop-lightroom.html">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>When I first got my Mac, I bought Apple's Aperture to handle photo editing and
management. When Lightroom 1 came out, I gave it a try and really enjoyed how
lightweight it felt. It's incredibly easy to use, and its catalogs are quite
small, relative to Aperture's. It is easily extendible, with custom plugins
for exporting photos and custom presets for one-click photo editing. I've since
stayed with Lightroom, and never looked back.</p>

<h3>Netflix (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/netflix/id363590051?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>I have a slight obsession with Star Trek: The Next Generation, and, more
recently, with Star Trek: Voyager. Netflix has been a wonderful means of
distraction when I need to escape to the twenty-fourth century for some R &amp; R.</p>

<h3>Pages (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pages/id361309726?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pages/id409201541?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Pages is similar to iA Writer, but built for presentation-geared reports and
papers. If the formatting matters, Pages is there to save the day. I wrote quite
a few lab reports on Pages for iOS.</p>

<h3>Paper (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pages/id361309726?mt=8">iPad</a>)</h3>

<p>Paper by FiftyThree is pretty freakin' awesome. It's incredibly agile, and very
robust. While I am no artist, it's great for drawing up a quick website mock-up
and sending it off to colleagues. I am still in search of the right stylus, however
&mdash; I am using the Bamboo stylus from Wacom, but I need a tip which has more
precision for use with Paper. Let me know if you know of one I should pick up.</p>

<h3>Sparrow (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sparrow/id492573565?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sparrow/id417250177?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>I have been using Sparrow since its private beta days, and I just love the thing.
Sparrow for Mac is a beaut' and Sparrow for iOS makes managing my Gmail accounts
so easy and painless, it's almost too good to be true.</p>

<h3>Spotify (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/spotify/id324684580?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="http://www.spotify.com/us/download/mac/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Unfortunately, I am not made of money, and my bank account resembles that which
one might expect of a poor college student. In my hopes to spend less on music,
I signed up for Spotify and have just loved it. I have discovered several new
artists that I have come to adore (can it get better than some Babyface or Marc
Broussard??), and for that, I am thankful. Spotify for iOS is a bit weird when
trying to initialize radio on a 3G connection, but it's something I am willing
to live with for the time being.</p>

<h3>TextMate 2 Alpha (<a href="http://blog.macromates.com/2011/textmate-2-0-alpha/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>As I mentioned above, I code endlessly. My trusty companion is TextMate 2. In 2006,
<a href="http://blog.dcxn.com">Nick Rowe</a> showed me what would become the text editor to
change my world. After learning all the key bindings, it was hard to switch when
I started learning more about vim. So I stuck with TextMate. When TextMate 2 Alpha
came out, I was never happier. Rebuilt from the ground up, it has all the memory
management I could have hoped for out of TextMate 1. I love this app with all of
my heart.</p>

<h3>Things 2 (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/spotify/id324684580?mt=8">iPhone</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/things/id407951449?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Pretty much the only reason I've been productive this year is due to Things.
I was a beta tester for Things Cloud and Things 2 (both Mac and iOS) and was
delighted to find that this task-management application suite so quickly synced
all of my tasks, and <em>never</em> failed. I've never lost anything with Things Cloud,
and that reliability is important, when it means the difference between getting
someting done, and forgetting about it.</p>

<h3>TuneIn Radio (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tunein-radio-pro-listen-to/id319295332?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>The BBC World Service News station is one that I have grown to love, many thanks
to TuneIn Radio. It gives the user the opportunity to listen to radio stations
being broadcast all around the world &mdash; even in different languages. I have
learned a great deal of German, listening to Deutsche-Welle Nachrichten in this
app. It works beautifully over 3G, too, which makes long car rides all the more
pleasant.</p>

<h3>Tweetbot for (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter-iphone/id428851691?mt=8">iPhone</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter-ipad/id498801050?mt=8">iPad</a>, and <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter/id557168941?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Last, but certainly not least, I must acknowledge my addiction to Twitter. When
I wake in the morning, I never fail to reach over, grab my iPhone, check my email,
then check my Twitter feed. It usually takes a long breakfast to get through
all of them, but I am able to change devices, due to syncing of my position via
Tweet Marker. Before Tweetbot, I used Twitter for iPhone 3.5.1 (before that horrid
redesign), but really wanted CloudApp support. Tweetbot was the natural alternative
and everyone raved about it. After a couple weeks of using Tweetbot on a daily
basis, I deleted Twitter for iPhone without hesitation. Tweetbot is the best
way to interface with Twitter on any Apple device.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Letter to Tom Preston-Werner]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T17:03:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm a huge advocate of static site generators and have always favoured <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> as my go-to static site generator.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, it's fallen out of active development. I've been trying to contact Tom Preston-Werner (<a href="https://github.com/mojombo">@mojombo</a>) about it, but so far: nothing. (To be fair, I have gotten two replies, but they were not productive other than saying that he was looking for new maintainers. That was May 2012.)</p>

<p>So here's my open letter to you, Tom, about saving   Jekyll from open-source oblivion.</p>

<blockquote><p>Tom,</p>

<p>Hope you had a pleasant weekend.</p>

<p>Here's what I wish to see happen with Jekyll:</p>

<ol>
<li>Start an Org on Github and move the Jekyll repo to that org</li>
<li>Add several maintainers to that org (I'd be happy to help out as a maintainer!)</li>
<li>Add another author or two to the Jekyll gem so that we can gem push and release new versions.</li>
<li>Give at least one other person access to push to the source of jekyllrb.com so that the docs can be updated</li>
</ol>


<p>Problem I'm trying to solve:</p>

<blockquote><p>Jekyll is incredibly popular and is an incredibly powerful tool, but is not being actively maintained centrally, so though the world around it is evolving, it is staying stagnant and plagued by the same issues it has been for the last four years.</p></blockquote>

<p>Solution:</p>

<blockquote><p>Add maintainers to Jekyll to help deal with issues, push new versions, and update the documentation when you don't have the time.</p></blockquote>

<p>The great thing about version control systems is that changes can always be reverted.</p>

<p>Thanks in advance for your attention to this problem and willingness to help it continue growing.</p>

<p>Warm Regards,<br>
Parker Moore</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iA Writer Needs Print Configuration]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/ia-writer-needs-print-configuration/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T16:41:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/ia-writer-needs-print-configuration</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have really adored iA Writer and use the app obsessively on my iPhone, iPad and Mac. It's arguably one of my most oft-used apps. I write all sorts of things with the app: blog posts/ideas (like this one), essays, lab reports -- even the occasional code snippet. It's my writing tool of choice, and I thank Information Architects for writing such an awesome app.</p>

<p>I also print out a lot of my writing. I like to edit by hand with a pen and paper. I like the beautiful typeface that iA Writer provides and the margins on 8.5" x 11" paper (US) are amazing. I've really enjoyed the almost typewriter-like essence of the print-outs which iA Writer provides.</p>

<p>I'd really love some more configuration options for printing, however. While I will undoubtedly hear the argument that iA Writer offers no configuration <em>on purpose</em>, I will argue that the "No Configuration Rule" must only apply to in-app writing, not to the manifestation of this writing in paper form.</p>

<p>The No Configuration Rule is supported by the fact that configuration and modification of the working environment is often a hindrance to one's ability to write awesome content. It's a distraction. But it's a distraction only when <em>writing</em>, not when printing. I'd say this No Configuration Rule thus can only be justified for writing, i.e. on;y be justified for the look and feel of the writing experience in the app.</p>

<p>But that's an argument with too many implications. Let's make it a bit smaller, to the size of a wish:</p>

<p>My only real wish for this app is to allow double-spaced print-outs. That's it. I want to be able to edit my papers double-spaced.</p>

<p>So what say you, Information Architects? Think it's possible? I'd really appreciate it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
