<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: story | Hey, I’m Parker.]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/categories/story/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-17T00:59:47-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Uncomfortable]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/06/03/uncomfortable/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-03T16:10:34-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/06/03/uncomfortable</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Members of the Cornell University Glee Club and Chorus were asked to perform at a wedding on campus yesterday, and as a member of the Glee Club, I volunteered to sing. This wedding, being a Catholic one, was quite traditional, and left me feeling quite uneasy about my participation in the ceremony.</p>

<p>I have renounced any belief in the Judeo-Christian God for about 8 years. I grew up in an Episcopalian church in Rochester, NY and it was quite a liberal experience. Though I appreciate what religion can do for many around the world, I find it stifling, and often quite demeaning. As I listened to the prayers, I was overwhelmed by a feeling of unease. Questions filled my head: <em>How can anyone subject themselves to complete obedience to something of which they know so little? How can anyone find this comforting, to relinquish control to some &quot;being&quot; that most likely does not exist? Why do members of our society, despite incredible evidence against it, continue to believe in such an archaic set of beliefs?</em></p>

<p>I found myself wishing I could get up and leave. My heart began to race, fueled by the &quot;fight-or-flight&quot; instinct. I felt threatened, not only personally, but also I felt a threat to our entire society. We see, on a practically <em>daily</em> basis, how the Abrahamic religions are holding us back in many different ways. We are paralyzed by our fear that disbelief will mean condemnation, but all forget that the concepts of hell and purgatory are Medieval conceptions fabricated by the Roman Catholic Church to provoke incredible fear. These conceptions are just as despicable, just as reprehensible, as the tithe. These conceptions invoke a fear that is very real, but it has been seen time and time again that obedience caused by means of fear always falls.</p>

<p>There is hope. The population of &quot;non-believers&quot;, those who do not profess a belief in the God of Abraham, is growing rapidly. With the ability of science to definitively answer questions that were historically answered by religious doctrines, we are able to let our belief in the Judeo-Christian God go. We no longer need a priest, an imam or a rabbi to interpret the scriptures for us &mdash; we have scientists that can do this for us! Our scientists, their theories based upon facts (things we <em>know</em> to be true, not just a guess or a belief), have given us verifiable beliefs. Skepticism is welcomed. It is a wonderful thing to be a part of the scientific world!</p>

<p>Listening to the prayers professing ultimate devotion to some being no one actually knows, I became uneasy. Our society can do better than this. We must be determined to live in a more fact-based society… <em>we must</em>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thank my lucky stars]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/05/30/thank-my-lucky-stars/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/05/30/thank-my-lucky-stars</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night, I experienced the most significant car trouble that has ever occurred while I was driving. As I and a couple friends were leaving the city of Rochester for home in our respective suburbs, I ran over a pothole that was quite large (it is Spring in a city which experiences incredible snowfall, so they are to be expected) and heard a thud and a &quot;whooooosshhh&quot;. I stopped the car.</p>

<p>I hopped out of the driver&#39;s seat and inspected the vehicle. My front left tire had popped and I was now riding on the rim. No good. I turn off the car and switch into crisis mode. <em>I&#39;ve done this before</em>, I think as I remember back to helping my father change the tire on the back of our minivan a year or so ago. The other guys in the car behind me (we had two cars, luckily) hop out to help. I grab the spare tire, jack and wrench from the trunk and begin the process. <em>Loosen the bolts. Jack up the car. Take out the bolts. Replace the tire with the spare. Reattach the bolts. Put the car back on the ground. Tighten the bolts.</em></p>

<p>As we are working on the car, we realize that the car is not on flat terrain. The road upon which we&#39;ve stopped is an incline. We jack up the car with incredible trepidation, with two guys on the lower end of the car, applying pressure to ensure that there are no issues with the car falling from the jack and ruining the axle.</p>

<p>All goes as planned and we lower the car. Once the car is on the ground, we notice that the spare is flat! Jeebus, this is annoying. Bereft of a pump or any other way of putting air into the tire, we&#39;re stuck. I finally cave and call AAA, only to find that I&#39;m not on the plan and that &quot;the plan covers [my father], not the vehicle.&quot; After about 15 minutes of calls (it&#39;s easily 12:15AM by this point), my father sorts it out and is able to convince AAA to add me to the plan. They give me a call and I&#39;m (finally) able to request a tow truck. Whew, that was annoying.</p>

<p>All while I&#39;m on the phone with AAA, I suggest to the other car that they head out (a couple of them had to wake up very early). They agree and go to leave, only to find that their car won&#39;t start. Now this is quite a turn of events. Two cars, out-of-commision on the highway very late at night &mdash; this is how horror films start.</p>

<p>As we&#39;re waiting for the tow truck to arrive, a friend and I are talking while keeping a look out. We see a tow truck drive by and we flag him down, but he&#39;s not the tow truck which was called for us. A kind-hearted guy, he agrees to help us out. He maneauvers his vehicle over to where my car was disabled and inspects the spare. He pumps it up and determines that it&#39;s not leaking! What joy! One car back to road-readiness.</p>

<p>The other tow truck arrives as we&#39;re working to blow up my tire and he
jumps the other vehicle. All is well.</p>

<p>Couldn&#39;t have asked to deal with this with better people. Was so glad
they were there to help. Thank my lucky stars.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Without the Internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/11/16/life-without-the-internet/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-16T00:13:08-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/11/16/life-without-the-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I write this, Cornell&#39;s network is down. It happened at about midnight - all of a sudden, everyone was receiving timeout errors and refused connection errors. I had some more offline work to do, so it didn&#39;t worry me too much, but I found myself anxious. I was anxious about the fact that I couldn&#39;t connect. In mere moments, the full realization that my connection to the world at large (alas, I have a dumb phone) was severed. After a minute or two of contemplation, I felt an overwhelming sense of calm: the world that I am in &mdash; the world of Cornell, and of Ithaca &mdash; was still very much accessible to me. The lack of an internet connection didn&#39;t stop me from going down to the café and enjoying a cappuccino and a nice book, nor did it hinder my ability to see those I care most about here. I felt at peace.</p>

<p>In addition to a newfound realization for what is around me here at Cornell, the internet&#39;s incessant nagging was finally put to rest. No more &quot;1 Unread Message&quot; or &quot;248 Articles to Read&quot;. My lack of connection with the world was, for a moment, a wonderful escape from the unending barrage of information the internet presents on a daily basis.</p>

<p>This got me thinking. Born in the early nineties, I have always known the internet. In fact, I have never known a world without the internet, the personal computer, cell phones, and much more. I am truly a child of the information age. But have I been missing out on something? Constantly battling the perpetual influx of emails, tweets, status updates, and so forth, I wonder if I lose sight of ourselves. Moreover, I wonder if <em>we</em> lose sight of <em>ourselves</em>. (I know I&#39;m not alone when it comes to the relentless flow of information heading my way.) I have a moment, indeed many moments, to truly self-reflect. This, I do believe, is what my generation lacks the most: time for self-reflection.</p>

<p>Thus, I challenge you today, to turn off your internet for an hour, or perhaps two. You may find yourself delighted to see what is awaiting you on the other side.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Getting Busy At Cornell]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/08/30/getting-busy-at-cornell/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-30T10:21:56-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/08/30/getting-busy-at-cornell</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;ve been at <a href="http://www.cornell.edu/">Cornell</a> for a little over a week and I can honestly admit I&#39;ve never been this busy. Thanks to my time at McGill, I have been able to manage my time well, but this is a new level of busy for me!</p>

<p>Coursework has been relatively do-able; I&#39;ve had 3 assignments and 7 readings to do. All in all, not too bad for 3 days of classes. Judging from what I know at this moment, <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=90911"><strong>CS2110</strong></a> is probably going to be the most work. Much of the theory behind the algorithms and mathematical problems is new to me and I suspect that will be the most difficult aspect of this class. <a href="http://www.infosci.cornell.edu/ugrad/CalsMajor.htm"><strong>INFO1300</strong></a> (Intro to Web Design), if I can&#39;t obtain an exemption from the course, will be a cinch. I really don&#39;t expect any issues with that class at all. <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=93470"><strong>INFO 2040</strong></a> will be lots of work, but the concepts we&#39;re learning don&#39;t seem too difficult to grasp. It&#39;s also a huge class, so there&#39;s plenty of opportunity to ask questions to others. It has a good reputation, too. <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=91639"><strong>EDUC2710</strong></a> is already turning out to be one of my favourite classes. Going to be a <em>lot</em> of work, but it&#39;ll be worth it. I was recently given permission to enroll in <a href="http://courses.cornell.edu/preview_course.php?catoid=12&amp;coid=90949&amp;print"><strong>CS4999</strong></a>, a class where I conduct research and write web apps for college credit. All in all, a good deal.</p>

<p>Cornell offers wonderful academics, but I would argue that the extracurricular opportunities rival those in the academic world. I have chosen to get involved in the music scene here, having been accepted into the <a href="http://www.gleeclub.com/">Cornell Glee Club</a> just last night! A Cappella auditions are this week, and I&#39;m still working on those. I&#39;m also hoping to get involved with the <a href="http://www.cornellsun.com/">Cornell Daily Sun</a> as a web developer. There are a couple other clubs I&#39;m looking into, but those are sort of on hold while auditions ensue.</p>

<p>In addition to all of this, I am a free-lance web developer/designer. I&#39;m really excited to continue my Cornell experience. It&#39;s amazing here and I don&#39;t want to waste even one minute. Let&#39;s end in song:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Far above Cayuga&#39;s waters,<br />
  With its waves of blue,<br />
  Stands our noble Alma Mater,<br />
  Glorious to view.<br />
  <br />
  Lift the chorus, speed it onward,<br />
  Loud her praises tell;<br />
  Hail to thee, our Alma Mater!<br />
  Hail, all hail, Cornell!<br />
  <br />
  Far above the busy humming<br />
  Of the bustling town,<br />
  Reared against the arch of heaven,<br />
  Looks she proudly down.<br />
  <br />
  Lift the chorus, speed it onward,<br />
  Loud her praises tell;<br />
  Hail to thee, our Alma Mater!<br />
  Hail, all hail, Cornell!</p>
</blockquote>

<p>I look forward to sharing more with you about Cornell and my experiences here.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
