<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: future | Hey, I’m Parker.]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/categories/future/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-17T00:59:47-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On The Future]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/09/25/on-the-future/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-25T13:11:10-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2011/09/25/on-the-future</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Following my arrival at Cornell, I began considering my future much more seriously. What would I like to see myself doing in 5 years? How will I get myself there?</p>

<p>To answer the former question, I see myself working in my career in five years. I will complete my B.S. in Information Science in 2014 and will follow that up with a one-year M.P.S. in the same department. That brings me to May 2015, only four years and a half from how. I expect to find myself applying for full-time positions the previous semester at various tech firms such as Google, Etsy (my hands-down favorite), Hulu and other young firms. I&#39;m working to build up my <a href="http://parkermoore.de/resume/">resumé</a> and fortify my skill set with new languages, algorithms and the like.</p>

<p>Writing this, however, and having been a philosophy/political science/linguistics major last year at McGill, I can&#39;t help by wonder if it&#39;s all worth it. Our society dictates a certain path for future success. Those who are successful have earned a degree from an accredited institution such as Cornell, have perhaps pursued a graduate degree and go off to find a job that pays well. If only we valued our own happiness as much as our salaries, the world might be a better place. I hear talk of hopes to be millionaires and billionaires from students on campus and something about that appalls me but simultaneously excites me. Wouldn&#39;t it be great to have a net worth of over one million dollars?</p>

<p>But we mustn&#39;t forget that some of the happiest people on Earth live on a couple dollars a day. I wish to discover what it is they have that we are so lacking. Quality relationships with our families (the divorce rate is sky-high and I hear stories left and right about parents abandoning their children), perhaps? Or possibly an overwhelming sense of self-worth that our magazines and tabloids deny from us? If we are to have a happier future, collectively, then surely we must figure this out.</p>

<p>Pondering my future is a constant source of worry; not because I don&#39;t think I will be able to find a job, but because I don&#39;t wish to be a slave to my job nor dislike it. Do you know what I mean?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
