<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: politics | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/politics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-05T22:49:11-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carlin Was Right]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/06/26/carlin-was-right/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T12:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/06/26/carlin-was-right</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The late comedian George Carlin was never skiddish about sharing his opinion of the
country and of the human race. "It's all going downhill," he would say. The decline of
objective rationality sewed our fate: we're fucked.</p>

<p>We're fucked on foreign relations.<br />
We're fucked on domestic freedoms.<br />
We're fucked on freedom from discrimination.<br />
We're fucked on climate change.<br />
We're fucked on economic prosperity.<br />
We're fucked on everything, because objective rationality is dead.<br /></p>

<p>We haven't done right by each other and we haven't done right by our planet.
We're the scourge of the Earth and it's weeks like this one that make me wish we had blown
ourselves to oblivion during the Cold War. The cockroaches would at least be better
caretakers of this world than we are.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Rid of Senate Prayer]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/09/get-rid-of-senate-prayer/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T18:17:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/09/get-rid-of-senate-prayer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier today, I was watching a <a href="http://www.c-spanvideo.org/program/SenateSession4967">C-SPAN video</a> of a U.S. Senate session on
February 1, 2012. This was the first time I had ever watched a Senate session
from the beginning and, to my surprise, they began with a prayer.</p>

<p>Hold up. A prayer? In a session of one of our government's highest legislative
bodies?! I suppose I shouldn't be too surprised, what with the (often crazy)
Religious Right getting after the government with Bible-backed policies and
all. It was nevertheless astonishing to see the institutionalization of religion
in our government.</p>

<p>I generally like our government, but this changes everything. Man, I was angry.
I felt betrayed and undermined - like I was worth nothing to anyone in D.C.</p>

<p>So I wrote to my senators:</p>

<blockquote><p>Dear Senator,</p>

<p>I wish to ask for the Senator's thoughts on the opening prayer which begins a
Senate session. I have done my research and see that this prayer has been a
part of Senate procedure since 1789 and was recommended by Benjamin Franklin
about two years previous, but I question its place in our secular government.
It is, frankly, inappropriate that any governmental body in our United States
of America be so closely tied to one religious creed in a nation with many
hundreds and thousands of religious belief systems. I will not deny that
religion is a part of politics - a belief in a certain religious creed often
results in an election win - but it has absolutely no place in governance.
It is insulting to think that any one religion is given special treatment in
our governments.</p>

<p>I ask the Senator to introduce a bill which will put an end to this Senate
Prayer, for, while Mr. Franklin may have been right in 1789, he is most
certainly wrong now. We have moved past a blind reliance on God, and it is,
now more than ever, a hindrance on our Great Government.
God's interference in our government has forced limited civil rights for
minorities, was a rationale for slavery, and is still fighting against a
Woman's Right to Choose, a Citizen's Right To Marry Whomever He or She Wishes,
Scientific Advancement in many fields and so on.</p>

<p>It is our imperative as citizens to think of each other first and to respect
the different viewpoints and beliefs of our fellow Americans. Honoring any
religion on our Senate floor is a betrayal of this principle, and it must be
stopped.</p>

<p>Thank you,<br />
Parker Moore<br />
Constituent</p></blockquote>

<p>If you care about religious freedom at all, I would urge you to do the same.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Mustn't Idle]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/21/we-mustnt-idle/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-21T21:12:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/21/we-mustnt-idle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our legacies on this Beautiful Earth are inextricably tied to the work we do, the
principles we stand for and the messages we spread. The apathetic nature of many of my
peers nowadays is heresy to the nth degree, and we can no longer stand idly by and watch
young people refusing to talk about the hard issues. If we’re to make any progress and
maintain this More Perfect Union, we had better get our act together and stand and fight
for the things we believe in.</p>

<p>It comes with a price, however. We must be informed. We must read the arguments of the
other side, debate them and reformulate our stance given the new evidence. In the same
way Newton used this inductive methods to formulate his three famous Natural Laws, we
must start with a problem we observe in our society, generalize a solution in the form
of legislation, judicial action or grassroots campaigning, and revise our message as new
information becomes available.</p>

<p>It is not enough to let Gov majors, English majors and law students run the country,
making sweeping decisions about how we may live our lives. It is not enough to defer to
those with means and wealth – those with the ability to run a traditional campaign for
public office and influence those in public office – in fact, it is the worst offense to
this Great Nation to allow the aristocracy of special interets to continue determining
the rule of law. We must stand up, as citizens, and fight for what sparks fire in our
bellies! We must stand up, as citizens, and say “enough is enough” to special interests
and lobbyists who control Washington. Now is our time. If our country is to change for
the better, it will be because we – the citizens – made our voices heard and fought with
much gnashing of teeth for what we believe in and what we know is right.</p>

<p>This is the imperative of our generation. Let us act!</p>

<p>This post was originally published on <a href="https://medium.com/i-m-h-o/d5bf40927b1a">Medium</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do Not Single Out the Democrats - This is About Everyone]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/01/do-not-single-out-the-democrats-equals-this-is-about-everyone/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-01T00:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/01/do-not-single-out-the-democrats-equals-this-is-about-everyone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just read an <a href="http://www.upworthy.com/omg-google-tucker-carlson-and-gay-marriage?c=fea">appalling story by <em>Upworthy</em></a> that singles out 10 Democratic
senators who do not support full marriage equality for gays and lesbians. This
article is an absolute disgrace. <em>Upworthy</em> (and the <em>Huffington Post</em> for that
matter) should not be singling out Democrats who do not believe in same-sex
marriage as though it's some unnatural digression from the widely-accepted
democratic platform. No, they should be listing <strong>every</strong> senator that does
not support same-sex marriage.</p>

<p>It is not a fundamental tenant of the democratic platform. It is a fundamental
tenant of reason, of American law, and of human equality. There is no good
reason every congressperson should not support same-sex marriage. This is not
about party lines. This is about human dignity and equality in the eyes of the
law.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
