<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: politics | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/politics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-22T00:37:33-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fix the Government: Open-Source Legislation]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/10/22/fix-the-government-open-source-legislation/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-22T19:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/10/22/fix-the-government-open-source-legislation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>The following post was first written for a class at Cornell University taught
by Phoebe Sengers called "Designing Technologies for Social Impact".</em></p>

<hr />

<p>We have a rather significant problem in the U.S. Indeed, our government seems to
be malfunctioning in a rather obvious and irresponsible way. The question of
today is simply: can it be fixed? If so, how?</p>

<p>One must first examine the problem and its root cause. The problem of
malfunction is most basically the conflict of multiple competing interests
without proper ideological or procedural basis for dialogue. The root cause of
this is that the existing platforms for dialogue (meetings, letters, rallies,
news spots) are severely outdated. What worked pre-internet is not passing the
test of time.</p>

<p>In particular, the legislative process is slow, dilapidated, and closed. This
leads to laws with earmarks and loopholes, confusing language and unnecessary
provisions. What if the law were made out in the open, for everyone to see, the
way open-source software is made? Version control and online access to bills
in-the-works as well as laws would certainly improve transparency. The Library
of Congress runs a system called THOMAS which is updated about daily, but the
bills aren't organized logically and the user interface is fair at best.</p>

<p>The open-source legislation system envisioned here is based on an open-source
software system called GitHub. GitHub is setup like so: users and organizations
own repositories of code, text or binary documents. Each repository contains the
entire history of a particular set of documents as well as the "master" version,
or the latest repository-owner(s)-approved version of the document(s). Each
repository uses a version control system called git to keep track of the
information about the documents it contains: current versions as well as
previous versions. What is unique about this system, and the incredible strength
it offers for open legislation, is the concept of a "diff". A "diff" is simply
the difference between a document at one point in time (referred to as a
"revision") and the same document at a different point in time. Each repository
can be "forked" (cloned to a user's own profile for editing) by a user; this
offers the most significant freedom of open-source, which is that anyone has the
freedom to modify a copy of the source and suggest changes to the main project
based on those derivative works. In GitHub parlance, the suggestion for a change
is called a "pull request," but this term need not be adopted by this new
system.</p>

<p>To illustrate the design of the ideal system:</p>

<ol>
<li>Use git derivative for prose editing, rather than (line-by-line) code editing</li>
<li>Be online, accessible by anyone</li>
<li>Offer input from anyone in any form (suggested changes or just comments)</li>
<li>Do not make differentiation between users other than repository owner &amp;
non-owner (those with direct access to the repository and those who can fork
and suggest changes, but can't incorporate those changes themselves)</li>
<li><p>Each repository is a proposed bill owned by the deciding body at the given
time during the legislative process as dictated by the U.S. Constitution.
Each repository contains a text file for each sub-segment of the proposed
bill as well as a rationale or goal, e.g.
  . (root)
  |
  |-- README.txt (rationale, goal(s) of bill, and other meta info)
  |-- section01.txt
  |-- section02.txt
  |
  ...</p></li>
<li><p>The entire process of the creation and formulation of the law is public and
open insofar as the culture can push for this</p></li>
<li>Moderator of some sort to ensure comments are productive (usually repo
owner). All of the comments that are hidden still exist inline and can be
shown by any reader of the comment thread</li>
<li>Membership of individual lawmakers in committees and other larger bodies
reflected in membership of organization accounts on the platform, which gives
them access to directly changing the legislation they have access to through
their organizational memberships</li>
<li>Offer "points of interest" as a means of discussion about a particular aspect
of a bill without the need to suggest changes. Can ask anything from "why is
this section worded this way?" to "what are the implications of this on
agricultural development in Upstate New York?" No question is too dumb and
all of them require an answer insofar as they are productive and relevant.</li>
<li>Easy citation of preexisting laws and other bills to allow for discussion
surrounding conflict or other interference</li>
<li>Access to signing letters written by President (usually interpretations of
pieces of the law for purposes of execution of the law)</li>
<li>Easy viewing of votes on final versions of bills (who, when, did it pass?,
etc)</li>
<li>Means of mentioning lawmakers in a comment if comment is directed at them,
or question is asked directly of them</li>
<li>Links to more information about execution by Executive &amp; other related
policy/law</li>
<li>Comments and changes can only be created from user accounts, e.g. David
Skorton can suggest a change, but Cornell University cannot.</li>
<li>Users can subscribe to updates from a bill repository and receive all
information about changes that are made and discussions that occur.</li>
</ol>


<p>One negative aspect of this approach is volume and the issues that come
therefrom (see: student's answer on Piazza page linked to below). As the number
of collaborators grows, the ability for those with direct access to the bills to
handle suggestions for modification is greatly diminished. How are the interests
of the few vs. those of the many weighed (e.g. individual comment vs comment from
organization such as NAACP)? From the perspective of the way government works
already, aides of the legislators who have access to the repositories will also
have mirrored access to accept and discuss changes and questions from citizens.
As each law is its own repository, the load is distributed over the many
hundreds of bill repositories being considered. Additionally, Nissenbaum &amp;
Benkler discuss the idea of self-selection and volunteerism as an element of
open-source. This applies very much so to the scalability of open-source
legislation and responses to citizens. If a citizen is not interested in a
particular bill, that citizen will not involve himself or herself with the
creation of that bill. This self-selection will greatly reduce the number of
individuals with whom the maintainers of the bills will have to contend with in
discussion about a bill and suggestions for change.</p>

<p>Ultimately, this idea is predicated on the idea that citizens, when given the
right tools, can reach compromise and have productive discussions to "get the
job done" efficiently and accurately.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Carlin Was Right]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/06/26/carlin-was-right/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T12:48:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/06/26/carlin-was-right</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The late comedian George Carlin was never skiddish about sharing his opinion of the
country and of the human race. "It's all going downhill," he would say. The decline of
objective rationality sewed our fate: we're fucked.</p>

<p>We're fucked on foreign relations.<br />
We're fucked on domestic freedoms.<br />
We're fucked on freedom from discrimination.<br />
We're fucked on climate change.<br />
We're fucked on economic prosperity.<br />
We're fucked on everything, because objective rationality is dead.<br /></p>

<p>We haven't done right by each other and we haven't done right by our planet.
We're the scourge of the Earth and it's weeks like this one that make me wish we had blown
ourselves to oblivion during the Cold War. The cockroaches would at least be better
caretakers of this world than we are.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Rid of Senate Prayer]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/09/get-rid-of-senate-prayer/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T18:17:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/09/get-rid-of-senate-prayer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier today, I was watching a <a href="http://www.c-spanvideo.org/program/SenateSession4967">C-SPAN video</a> of a U.S. Senate session on
February 1, 2012. This was the first time I had ever watched a Senate session
from the beginning and, to my surprise, they began with a prayer.</p>

<p>Hold up. A prayer? In a session of one of our government's highest legislative
bodies?! I suppose I shouldn't be too surprised, what with the (often crazy)
Religious Right getting after the government with Bible-backed policies and
all. It was nevertheless astonishing to see the institutionalization of religion
in our government.</p>

<p>I generally like our government, but this changes everything. Man, I was angry.
I felt betrayed and undermined - like I was worth nothing to anyone in D.C.</p>

<p>So I wrote to my senators:</p>

<blockquote><p>Dear Senator,</p>

<p>I wish to ask for the Senator's thoughts on the opening prayer which begins a
Senate session. I have done my research and see that this prayer has been a
part of Senate procedure since 1789 and was recommended by Benjamin Franklin
about two years previous, but I question its place in our secular government.
It is, frankly, inappropriate that any governmental body in our United States
of America be so closely tied to one religious creed in a nation with many
hundreds and thousands of religious belief systems. I will not deny that
religion is a part of politics - a belief in a certain religious creed often
results in an election win - but it has absolutely no place in governance.
It is insulting to think that any one religion is given special treatment in
our governments.</p>

<p>I ask the Senator to introduce a bill which will put an end to this Senate
Prayer, for, while Mr. Franklin may have been right in 1789, he is most
certainly wrong now. We have moved past a blind reliance on God, and it is,
now more than ever, a hindrance on our Great Government.
God's interference in our government has forced limited civil rights for
minorities, was a rationale for slavery, and is still fighting against a
Woman's Right to Choose, a Citizen's Right To Marry Whomever He or She Wishes,
Scientific Advancement in many fields and so on.</p>

<p>It is our imperative as citizens to think of each other first and to respect
the different viewpoints and beliefs of our fellow Americans. Honoring any
religion on our Senate floor is a betrayal of this principle, and it must be
stopped.</p>

<p>Thank you,<br />
Parker Moore<br />
Constituent</p></blockquote>

<p>If you care about religious freedom at all, I would urge you to do the same.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[We Mustn't Idle]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/22/we-mustnt-idle/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T02:12:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/22/we-mustnt-idle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our legacies on this Beautiful Earth are inextricably tied to the work we do, the
principles we stand for and the messages we spread. The apathetic nature of many of my
peers nowadays is heresy to the nth degree, and we can no longer stand idly by and watch
young people refusing to talk about the hard issues. If we’re to make any progress and
maintain this More Perfect Union, we had better get our act together and stand and fight
for the things we believe in.</p>

<p>It comes with a price, however. We must be informed. We must read the arguments of the
other side, debate them and reformulate our stance given the new evidence. In the same
way Newton used this inductive methods to formulate his three famous Natural Laws, we
must start with a problem we observe in our society, generalize a solution in the form
of legislation, judicial action or grassroots campaigning, and revise our message as new
information becomes available.</p>

<p>It is not enough to let Gov majors, English majors and law students run the country,
making sweeping decisions about how we may live our lives. It is not enough to defer to
those with means and wealth – those with the ability to run a traditional campaign for
public office and influence those in public office – in fact, it is the worst offense to
this Great Nation to allow the aristocracy of special interets to continue determining
the rule of law. We must stand up, as citizens, and fight for what sparks fire in our
bellies! We must stand up, as citizens, and say “enough is enough” to special interests
and lobbyists who control Washington. Now is our time. If our country is to change for
the better, it will be because we – the citizens – made our voices heard and fought with
much gnashing of teeth for what we believe in and what we know is right.</p>

<p>This is the imperative of our generation. Let us act!</p>

<p>This post was originally published on <a href="https://medium.com/i-m-h-o/d5bf40927b1a">Medium</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do Not Single Out the Democrats - This is About Everyone]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/01/do-not-single-out-the-democrats-equals-this-is-about-everyone/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-01T00:23:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/04/01/do-not-single-out-the-democrats-equals-this-is-about-everyone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just read an <a href="http://www.upworthy.com/omg-google-tucker-carlson-and-gay-marriage?c=fea">appalling story by <em>Upworthy</em></a> that singles out 10 Democratic
senators who do not support full marriage equality for gays and lesbians. This
article is an absolute disgrace. <em>Upworthy</em> (and the <em>Huffington Post</em> for that
matter) should not be singling out Democrats who do not believe in same-sex
marriage as though it's some unnatural digression from the widely-accepted
democratic platform. No, they should be listing <strong>every</strong> senator that does
not support same-sex marriage.</p>

<p>It is not a fundamental tenant of the democratic platform. It is a fundamental
tenant of reason, of American law, and of human equality. There is no good
reason every congressperson should not support same-sex marriage. This is not
about party lines. This is about human dignity and equality in the eyes of the
law.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
