<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: open-source | Musings of Parker J. Moore]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/blog/categories/open-source/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-23T13:29:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker J. Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Taking Over Someone Else's Open-Source Project]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/11/04/taking-over-someone-elses-open-source-project/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-04T21:23:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/11/04/taking-over-someone-elses-open-source-project</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last December (2012), <a href="http://tom.preston-werner.com">Tom Preston-Werner</a> granted me <a href="/images/mojombo-added-parkr-to-jekyll.png">push &amp; pull access to
mojombo/jekyll</a>. I had written a <a href="/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner/">letter to Tom about the future of Jekyll</a>
and after a bit of persistence on my part, he relented:</p>

<p><img src="/images/mojombo-added-parkr-to-jekyll.png" alt="mojombo added parkr to mojombo/jekyll"></p>

<p>After a somewhat lengthy (and <a href="/images/jekyll-shall-inherit-the-earth.png">amusing</a>) conversation via Skype, I knew what
Tom&#39;s priorities were for the project and where I could help. I started off
trimming down the number of open issues. At the time, they numbered just over 300.
After a quick visit to Buffalo to tackle some issues with <a href="http://quaran.to">Nick Quaranto</a> at a
Buffalo <a href="http://openhack.github.io">OpenHack</a> meetup at <a href="http://coworkbuffalo.com">CoworkBuffalo</a>, we were down to fewer than 200
open issues. I continued to work through them (much to my parents&#39; dismay) all
through Winter Break. I was making good progress in the triage process: I knew
what many of the problems were with v0.12.1 and was formulating ideas about how
we might go about fixing them.</p>

<p><img src="/images/jekyll-shall-inherit-the-earth.png" alt="jekyll shall inherit the earth"></p>

<p>In January, I flew out to San Francisco to visit my sister for a week. I setup a
meeting with Tom to talk more about Jekyll and a plan for moving forward to a
v1.0.0 release. After about an hour or so at GitHub&#39;s office in SoMa, talking
through various PR&#39;s, Tom said I could start merging pull requests.</p>

<p>Consultation with Tom was challenging (he runs a multi-million dollar company
after all), as it was increasingly difficult for him to find time for Jekyll.
Despite <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/issues/578#issuecomment-11414645">announcing that he was going to commit some of his &quot;20% time&quot; to Jekyll</a>,
he eventually abandoned that as impractical. As time went on, I received fewer
replies to my emails and eventually stopped sending anything that didn&#39;t
absolutely <em>require</em> Tom&#39;s input.</p>

<p>In March, I knew I needed more help. Tom wasn&#39;t able to give much time and I
was trying to tackle this project alone. I had noticed that <a href="http://mattr.info">Matt Rogers</a>
shared my vision for Jekyll, so I asked Tom to add him on as a contributor to
the repo. By v1.0.3, he had started merging pull requests like a BAW$ and was
the sanity to my ridiculously-obsessed, inexperienced mind. Since Matt joined, I
haven&#39;t really heard much from Tom. I write the occasional email and get the
occasional reply but he&#39;s essentially phased out of the normal development of
Jekyll. Matt &amp; I have essentially taken over the project altogether.</p>

<p>By May, we were ready to ship v1.0.0. With the help of all the amazing
contributors, Matt, and my many mentors along the way, I finally ran
<code>rake release</code> for 1.0. The project was ours.</p>

<p>Since realizing that this product has few constraints outside of those I&#39;ve
constructed for it in my mind (no one is going to tell me, &quot;No, you may not
implement that feature or add that enhancement&quot; without a valid argument as to
my solution&#39;s invalidity), I&#39;ve been thinking about what it means to take over
someone else&#39;s project. <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/commit/d189e05d236769c1e5594af9db4d6eacb86fc16e">Jekyll is 5 years old.</a> I wasn&#39;t there in 2008 when
it was first born as <code>autoblog</code>. Jekyll has changed a lot, as has its vision and
purpose. It&#39;s used by lots of people now, whether via <a href="http://pages.github.com">GitHub Pages</a> or
locally.</p>

<p>Taking over someone else&#39;s project takes a deep understanding of what the
project is and what it should be. As much as I wish Jekyll could make me
kräuterquark, that&#39;s outside the scope of the project. Developing that lens is
crucial when taking over someone else&#39;s project.</p>

<p>Mentoring on the part of the original owner/previous maintainer(s) is
exceedingly significant in the development of this critical lens. I am so
grateful that I was able to meet up with Tom back in January and to have some
amount of input from him as I understood what the project should be.</p>

<p>It would be ill-advised to take over someone else&#39;s project without a partner.
Once Matt joined the team, Tom was able to step back into a much lesser role.
If I had tried to do what I did without any guidance (or at least sanity
checks), Jekyll v1.0.0 would have been a complete shit-show.</p>

<p>Trust in the community must also be earned. If people highly doubted my ability
to handle Jekyll, Tom would have likely removed me and found a replacement. I
argued a lot and got into some pretty heated debates at the beginning. There
were a couple people who didn&#39;t share the vision that I had inherited from Tom
and stopped contributing to the project altogether. I feel like we now have a
pretty great community around Jekyll and are able to help each other out and
share cool plugins and sites that we made for/with Jekyll.</p>

<p>Taking over someone else&#39;s open-source project was new terrain for me in
December, and still is today. It can be successful with the right amount of
mentoring and gradual removal of trusted feedback by the previous maintainer(s).</p>

<p>With some old projects that are brought back to life by the passing of the
torch, the new maintainers are able to experience the added bonus of feeling
like Frankenstein, which, I will say, is a pretty cool feeling.</p>

<p><img src="/images/it-lives.jpg" alt="igor"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fix the Government: Open-Source Legislation]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/10/22/fix-the-government-open-source-legislation/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-22T19:45:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/10/22/fix-the-government-open-source-legislation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>The following post was first written for a class at Cornell University taught
by Phoebe Sengers called &quot;Designing Technologies for Social Impact&quot;.</em></p>

<hr>

<p>We have a rather significant problem in the U.S. Indeed, our government seems to
be malfunctioning in a rather obvious and irresponsible way. The question of
today is simply: can it be fixed? If so, how?</p>

<p>One must first examine the problem and its root cause. The problem of
malfunction is most basically the conflict of multiple competing interests
without proper ideological or procedural basis for dialogue. The root cause of
this is that the existing platforms for dialogue (meetings, letters, rallies,
news spots) are severely outdated. What worked pre-internet is not passing the
test of time.</p>

<p>In particular, the legislative process is slow, dilapidated, and closed. This
leads to laws with earmarks and loopholes, confusing language and unnecessary
provisions. What if the law were made out in the open, for everyone to see, the
way open-source software is made? Version control and online access to bills
in-the-works as well as laws would certainly improve transparency. The Library
of Congress runs a system called THOMAS which is updated about daily, but the
bills aren&#39;t organized logically and the user interface is fair at best.</p>

<p>The open-source legislation system envisioned here is based on an open-source
software system called GitHub. GitHub is setup like so: users and organizations
own repositories of code, text or binary documents. Each repository contains the
entire history of a particular set of documents as well as the &quot;master&quot; version,
or the latest repository-owner(s)-approved version of the document(s). Each
repository uses a version control system called git to keep track of the
information about the documents it contains: current versions as well as
previous versions. What is unique about this system, and the incredible strength
it offers for open legislation, is the concept of a &quot;diff&quot;. A &quot;diff&quot; is simply
the difference between a document at one point in time (referred to as a
&quot;revision&quot;) and the same document at a different point in time. Each repository
can be &quot;forked&quot; (cloned to a user&#39;s own profile for editing) by a user; this
offers the most significant freedom of open-source, which is that anyone has the
freedom to modify a copy of the source and suggest changes to the main project
based on those derivative works. In GitHub parlance, the suggestion for a change
is called a &quot;pull request,&quot; but this term need not be adopted by this new
system.</p>

<p>To illustrate the design of the ideal system:</p>

<ol>
<li>Use git derivative for prose editing, rather than (line-by-line) code editing</li>
<li>Be online, accessible by anyone</li>
<li>Offer input from anyone in any form (suggested changes or just comments)</li>
<li>Do not make differentiation between users other than repository owner &amp;
non-owner (those with direct access to the repository and those who can fork
and suggest changes, but can&#39;t incorporate those changes themselves)</li>
<li><p>Each repository is a proposed bill owned by the deciding body at the given
time during the legislative process as dictated by the U.S. Constitution.
Each repository contains a text file for each sub-segment of the proposed
bill as well as a rationale or goal, e.g.
 . (root)
 |
 |-- README.txt (rationale, goal(s) of bill, and other meta info)
 |-- section01.txt
 |-- section02.txt
 |
 ...</p></li>
<li><p>The entire process of the creation and formulation of the law is public and
open insofar as the culture can push for this</p></li>
<li><p>Moderator of some sort to ensure comments are productive (usually repo
owner). All of the comments that are hidden still exist inline and can be
shown by any reader of the comment thread</p></li>
<li><p>Membership of individual lawmakers in committees and other larger bodies
reflected in membership of organization accounts on the platform, which gives
them access to directly changing the legislation they have access to through
their organizational memberships</p></li>
<li><p>Offer &quot;points of interest&quot; as a means of discussion about a particular aspect
of a bill without the need to suggest changes. Can ask anything from &quot;why is
this section worded this way?&quot; to &quot;what are the implications of this on
agricultural development in Upstate New York?&quot; No question is too dumb and
all of them require an answer insofar as they are productive and relevant.</p></li>
<li><p>Easy citation of preexisting laws and other bills to allow for discussion
surrounding conflict or other interference</p></li>
<li><p>Access to signing letters written by President (usually interpretations of
pieces of the law for purposes of execution of the law)</p></li>
<li><p>Easy viewing of votes on final versions of bills (who, when, did it pass?,
etc)</p></li>
<li><p>Means of mentioning lawmakers in a comment if comment is directed at them,
or question is asked directly of them</p></li>
<li><p>Links to more information about execution by Executive &amp; other related
policy/law</p></li>
<li><p>Comments and changes can only be created from user accounts, e.g. David
Skorton can suggest a change, but Cornell University cannot.</p></li>
<li><p>Users can subscribe to updates from a bill repository and receive all
information about changes that are made and discussions that occur.</p></li>
</ol>

<p>One negative aspect of this approach is volume and the issues that come
therefrom (see: student&#39;s answer on Piazza page linked to below). As the number
of collaborators grows, the ability for those with direct access to the bills to
handle suggestions for modification is greatly diminished. How are the interests
of the few vs. those of the many weighed (e.g. individual comment vs comment from
organization such as NAACP)? From the perspective of the way government works
already, aides of the legislators who have access to the repositories will also
have mirrored access to accept and discuss changes and questions from citizens.
As each law is its own repository, the load is distributed over the many
hundreds of bill repositories being considered. Additionally, Nissenbaum &amp;
Benkler discuss the idea of self-selection and volunteerism as an element of
open-source. This applies very much so to the scalability of open-source
legislation and responses to citizens. If a citizen is not interested in a
particular bill, that citizen will not involve himself or herself with the
creation of that bill. This self-selection will greatly reduce the number of
individuals with whom the maintainers of the bills will have to contend with in
discussion about a bill and suggestions for change.</p>

<p>Ultimately, this idea is predicated on the idea that citizens, when given the
right tools, can reach compromise and have productive discussions to &quot;get the
job done&quot; efficiently and accurately.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Jekyll 1.0 Released]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-06T00:59:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/05/06/jekyll-1-dot-0-released</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today, I&#39;m proud to announce the release of Jekyll 1.0. There are a million
goodies and fixes to enjoy, and we&#39;re (the still-active Jekyll core team
members: Tom, Matt and I) really excited to share this first major release
with you. Be sure to follow <a href="http://twitter.com/jekyllrb">@jekyllrb</a> for
updates on future releases and links to cool plugins.</p>

<p>Some quick highlights:</p>

<ul>
<li>New subcommands: new, build, serve, and import</li>
<li>Amazing new docs at http://jekyllrb.com (thanks to @cobyism)</li>
<li><code>jekyll new</code> creates a new scaffold so you can get blogging even faster</li>
<li>Drafts, i.e. posts without dates</li>
<li>New &quot;excerpt&quot; feature on posts</li>
<li>Timezone configuration</li>
<li>&#39;gist&#39; liquid tag</li>
<li>Source directory protection</li>
</ul>

<p>... and <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/v1.0.0/History.txt">so much more</a>!</p>

<p>We also have an <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/docs/upgrading/">Upgrading</a> page that clarifies
some breaking changes and tips for upgrading to Jekyll 1.0.</p>

<p>As many of you know, Jekyll lay mostly stagnant for quite some time. At 0.11.2 and
0.12.0, it was pretty stable. It had some annoying bugs, but nothing much that
couldn&#39;t be worked around or monkey-patched.</p>

<p>After using Jekyll last summer to help build
<a href="http://cals.cornell.edu">Cornell&#39;s College of Agriculture and Life Sciences website</a>,
I took a renewed interest in seeing this project move forward. Last December,
Tom answered my offers to help with the development of Jekyll by adding me as
a contributor. I&#39;m happy to say that it has come a long way since then, and
I&#39;m very proud to be a part of a team that has pushed this project to new heights.</p>

<p>Thank you to everyone who submitted a pull request, and/or gave me advice along
the way. It has been great fun so far, and I look forward to working with you
all to push out future versions!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Open Letter to Tom Preston-Werner]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-11T17:03:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2012/12/11/an-open-letter-to-tom-preston-werner</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#39;m a huge advocate of static site generators and have always favoured <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a> as my go-to static site generator.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, it&#39;s fallen out of active development. I&#39;ve been trying to contact Tom Preston-Werner (<a href="https://github.com/mojombo">@mojombo</a>) about it, but so far: nothing. (To be fair, I have gotten two replies, but they were not productive other than saying that he was looking for new maintainers. That was May 2012.)</p>

<p>So here&#39;s my open letter to you, Tom, about saving   Jekyll from open-source oblivion.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Tom,</p>

<p>Hope you had a pleasant weekend.</p>

<p>Here&#39;s what I wish to see happen with Jekyll:</p>

<ol>
<li>Start an Org on Github and move the Jekyll repo to that org</li>
<li>Add several maintainers to that org (I&#39;d be happy to help out as a maintainer!)</li>
<li>Add another author or two to the Jekyll gem so that we can gem push and release new versions.</li>
<li>Give at least one other person access to push to the source of jekyllrb.com so that the docs can be updated</li>
</ol>

<p>Problem I&#39;m trying to solve:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Jekyll is incredibly popular and is an incredibly powerful tool, but is not being actively maintained centrally, so though the world around it is evolving, it is staying stagnant and plagued by the same issues it has been for the last four years.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Solution:</p>

<blockquote>
<p>Add maintainers to Jekyll to help deal with issues, push new versions, and update the documentation when you don&#39;t have the time.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>The great thing about version control systems is that changes can always be reverted.</p>

<p>Thanks in advance for your attention to this problem and willingness to help it continue growing.</p>

<p>Warm Regards,<br>
Parker Moore</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
