<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: apps | Hey, I’m Parker.]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/categories/apps/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/"/>
  <updated>2014-07-16T23:33:43-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parker Moore]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[parkrmoore@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Favourite Apps in 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/01/03/my-favourite-apps-in-2012/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-03T01:36:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.parkermoore.de/2013/01/03/my-favourite-apps-in-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Below is a list of the apps I wouldn&#39;t have wanted to live without this year.
To be fair to everyone, I&#39;ve listed them in alphabetical order.</p>

<p>I know some apps are missing links to various versions, but if I didn&#39;t use it,
then I felt it was best not to include a link to it on this list.</p>

<h3>101 Airborne (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/101-airborne/id531317549?mt=8">iPhone</a>)</h3>

<p>At this moment, this is one of only two games which I have installed on my iPhone.
I have thoroughly enjoyed playing this game, and it is incredibly well-done,
to boot.</p>

<h3>Diet Coda (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/diet-coda/id500906297?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>When I had to have the logic board in my MacBook Pro replaced, I had to hand in
my computer for a week. I am practically addicted to development, and this app
by Panic, Inc. of Portland, Oregon, served me well during those tough times.</p>

<h3>Dropbox (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/dropbox/id327630330?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/install">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Dropbox gives me the freedom to aimlessly roam between devices without losing
any progress. I can work on my mac for a bit, then pick up my iPad and resume
my work right then and there. Dropbox far surpasses the ease-of-use of competitors
such as Box.com, and its native Mac application is far less intrusive, as well.</p>

<h3>Google+ (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google+/id447119634?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>I&#39;m a social media weirdo. I have to try out every one that comes along. I even
tried out <a href="http://app.net">app.net</a> for a while (I still have an account there).
I started using this app far more after the amazing redesign which happened
right around Christmastime. It was indeed an enjoyable occasion. I use G+ to stay
in contact with friends who now work at Google and with friends of mine who insist
on Google-only living: an Android phone, Google+ to communicate (Messenger), and
Google Docs to collaborate.</p>

<h3>Google Chrome (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/chrome/id535886823?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://www.google.com/intl/en/chrome/browser/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Chrome on Mac is absolutely awesome. I use it obsessively.</p>

<p>Chrome on the iPhone is something I had to warm up to a bit more. It behaves far
differently than Safari on iOS and the controls are in completely different places.
After some adjustment, I&#39;ve come to appreciate its incredible flexibility and
strength in the mobile realm.</p>

<h3>Google Maps (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google-maps/id585027354?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>Apple Maps has yet to lead me to a hospital that isn&#39;t there, or on a road that has
been demolished, but I still missed the Google Maps speed and accuracy. I have also
found that Google Maps is far better for finding nearby amenities, such as coffee,
gas, and food.</p>

<h3>Google Translate (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/google-translate/id414706506?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>While I am relatively proficient in the language, learning German is a process.
I have found this app very helpful during my studies and even when having a
causal conversation over Skype in German.</p>

<h3>Gmail (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/gmail-email-from-google/id422689480?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>As with G+ above, the redesign really did it for me. It was, all of a sudden,
a reliable, beautiful, and agile experience, to use this app. It was incredibly
buggy before (it seemed to be a product from Google&#39;s insistence that online
mobile apps will be dominant, over native apps), but it has come a long way.</p>

<h3>iA Writer (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ia-writer/id392502056?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/ia-writer/id439623248?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Whenever I have a thought that I want to remember and ponder later, I write it
down in a note. This usually happens while I am on-the-go. I will then come
back later and review my thoughts and ideas in iA Writer for Mac. I am so thankful
that iA Writer offers syncing through services like iCloud and Dropbox.</p>

<p>I have even been known to write essays on my iPhone of 1000+ words while I walk
between classes, to dinner in Collegetown, and to and from rehearsals. Two of the
three &quot;A&quot; papers I wrote last year (one writes few papers when studying engineering)
were written almost entirely in iA Writer for iOS.</p>

<h3>Instapaper (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/instapaper/id288545208?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>After much consideration, I decided to include this app on my list. I have used
Instapaper for many years now, and have truly enjoyed using it. It has,
unforunately, become a repository for articles I&#39;d like to read, but probably
never will. I found Instapaper very useful, however, to pass the time during
long plane/car/bus rides, as well as long layovers between flights.</p>

<h3>iTerm2 (<a href="http://www.iterm2.com/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Almost all of my development before May this year was done in Terminal.app.
While I have appreciated its service, I decided to move on to iTerm2 upon a
recommendation from a friend. iTerm2 is light and doesn&#39;t have any weird &quot;Mac
baggage&quot; which Terminal.app does. It&#39;s simple to configure (though there are
far too many configuration options, in my opinion), and easy to use.</p>

<h3>Lightroom 4 (<a href="http://www.adobe.com/products/photoshop-lightroom.html">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>When I first got my Mac, I bought Apple&#39;s Aperture to handle photo editing and
management. When Lightroom 1 came out, I gave it a try and really enjoyed how
lightweight it felt. It&#39;s incredibly easy to use, and its catalogs are quite
small, relative to Aperture&#39;s. It is easily extendible, with custom plugins
for exporting photos and custom presets for one-click photo editing. I&#39;ve since
stayed with Lightroom, and never looked back.</p>

<h3>Netflix (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/netflix/id363590051?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>I have a slight obsession with Star Trek: The Next Generation, and, more
recently, with Star Trek: Voyager. Netflix has been a wonderful means of
distraction when I need to escape to the twenty-fourth century for some R &amp; R.</p>

<h3>Pages (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pages/id361309726?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pages/id409201541?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Pages is similar to iA Writer, but built for presentation-geared reports and
papers. If the formatting matters, Pages is there to save the day. I wrote quite
a few lab reports on Pages for iOS.</p>

<h3>Paper (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pages/id361309726?mt=8">iPad</a>)</h3>

<p>Paper by FiftyThree is pretty freakin&#39; awesome. It&#39;s incredibly agile, and very
robust. While I am no artist, it&#39;s great for drawing up a quick website mock-up
and sending it off to colleagues. I am still in search of the right stylus, however
&mdash; I am using the Bamboo stylus from Wacom, but I need a tip which has more
precision for use with Paper. Let me know if you know of one I should pick up.</p>

<h3>Sparrow (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sparrow/id492573565?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/sparrow/id417250177?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>I have been using Sparrow since its private beta days, and I just love the thing.
Sparrow for Mac is a beaut&#39; and Sparrow for iOS makes managing my Gmail accounts
so easy and painless, it&#39;s almost too good to be true.</p>

<h3>Spotify (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/spotify/id324684580?mt=8">iOS</a>, <a href="http://www.spotify.com/us/download/mac/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Unfortunately, I am not made of money, and my bank account resembles that which
one might expect of a poor college student. In my hopes to spend less on music,
I signed up for Spotify and have just loved it. I have discovered several new
artists that I have come to adore (can it get better than some Babyface or Marc
Broussard??), and for that, I am thankful. Spotify for iOS is a bit weird when
trying to initialize radio on a 3G connection, but it&#39;s something I am willing
to live with for the time being.</p>

<h3>TextMate 2 Alpha (<a href="http://blog.macromates.com/2011/textmate-2-0-alpha/">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>As I mentioned above, I code endlessly. My trusty companion is TextMate 2. In 2006,
<a href="http://blog.dcxn.com">Nick Rowe</a> showed me what would become the text editor to
change my world. After learning all the key bindings, it was hard to switch when
I started learning more about vim. So I stuck with TextMate. When TextMate 2 Alpha
came out, I was never happier. Rebuilt from the ground up, it has all the memory
management I could have hoped for out of TextMate 1. I love this app with all of
my heart.</p>

<h3>Things 2 (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/spotify/id324684580?mt=8">iPhone</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/things/id407951449?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Pretty much the only reason I&#39;ve been productive this year is due to Things.
I was a beta tester for Things Cloud and Things 2 (both Mac and iOS) and was
delighted to find that this task-management application suite so quickly synced
all of my tasks, and <em>never</em> failed. I&#39;ve never lost anything with Things Cloud,
and that reliability is important, when it means the difference between getting
someting done, and forgetting about it.</p>

<h3>TuneIn Radio (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tunein-radio-pro-listen-to/id319295332?mt=8">iOS</a>)</h3>

<p>The BBC World Service News station is one that I have grown to love, many thanks
to TuneIn Radio. It gives the user the opportunity to listen to radio stations
being broadcast all around the world &mdash; even in different languages. I have
learned a great deal of German, listening to Deutsche-Welle Nachrichten in this
app. It works beautifully over 3G, too, which makes long car rides all the more
pleasant.</p>

<h3>Tweetbot for (<a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter-iphone/id428851691?mt=8">iPhone</a>, <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter-ipad/id498801050?mt=8">iPad</a>, and <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tweetbot-for-twitter/id557168941?mt=12">Mac</a>)</h3>

<p>Last, but certainly not least, I must acknowledge my addiction to Twitter. When
I wake in the morning, I never fail to reach over, grab my iPhone, check my email,
then check my Twitter feed. It usually takes a long breakfast to get through
all of them, but I am able to change devices, due to syncing of my position via
Tweet Marker. Before Tweetbot, I used Twitter for iPhone 3.5.1 (before that horrid
redesign), but really wanted CloudApp support. Tweetbot was the natural alternative
and everyone raved about it. After a couple weeks of using Tweetbot on a daily
basis, I deleted Twitter for iPhone without hesitation. Tweetbot is the best
way to interface with Twitter on any Apple device.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
